有时比起人类我更喜欢动物
Yeah, I like animals better than people sometimes.
尤其是狗 狗最可爱
Especially dogs. Dogs are the best.
回家进门...
Every time you come through the door...
...它们对你就像一年没见的亲人
...they treat you as if they haven't seen you in a year.
狗最大的好处是...
The good thing about dogs...
...不同的人可以养不同的狗
...is they got different kinds of dogs for difforent kinds of people.
比如斗牛犬
Like pit bulls.
狗中之最
The dog of dogs.
斗牛犬能成为某些人最好的朋友...
Pit bull can be the right man's best friend...
...另一些人最可怕的敌人
...and the wrong man's worst enemy.
你要送狗给我当宠物 就送斗牛犬 给我...
Yeah, you gonna give me a dog, give me a pit bull. Give me...
..."拉乌尔" 好吗 奥马尔? 把拉乌尔给我
..."Raoull." Right, Omar? Give me Raoull.
我讨厌拉乌尔 闭嘴 混蛋
I fucking hate Raoull! Shut the fuck up, asshole!
该死的畜生不懂何时该闭嘴!
Son of a bitch don't know when to shut up!
他恨拉乌尔
Hates Raoull.
法利搞错了
Farley fucked up the list.
我能理解 我有只狗也这样 一只卷毛狗
Yeah, I can dig it, Omar. I had a dog like that. A poodle.
它不乱叫 可总是尿在地板上
She didn't bark, though. She pissed on the floor.
我讨厌它
Hated that dog.
可每当我心情不好时...
But if I was ever depressed...
...它就把头靠在我腿上...
...she'd lay her head in my lap...
...睁着大眼睛望着我...
...look up at me with those big old eyes...
...虽然我觉得我讨厌它...
...and even though I thought I hated that dog...
...其实我爱它
...I loved her.
你是不是也有这种感觉? 爱恨交加
It's like that, ain't it, Omar? That love-hate thing.
别再说废话了!
No more goddamned talk!
我不想等了 听见没有? 我要见我老婆!
I can't wait anymore, you hear me? I want my Wife!
让她马上来!
I want her up here.
不见我就杀了女儿
Or I'll do our daughter.
- 奥马尔 听我说 - 少废话
- Omar, listen to me. - No more fucking talking.
那贱女人不来 我就杀了女儿
I want that bitch, or I'll do the girl.
我在尽最大努力
Omar, I'm doing the best I can here, man.
我不伤害她
I'm not gonna hurt her.
只想让她看着我打烂自己的头
I just want her to see me blow my brains out.
让她和别人鬼混时...
I want her to think about that...
...想着我的样子
...when she's sucking that fat prick's cock.
罗曼劝不了他
Roman's losing him.
这家伙急了会杀孩子 我们马上冲进去
This guy goes' he could take that girl With him. We gotta go in.
再给丹尼点时间 已有进展了
We'll give Danny another minute. Not yet. He's pulled out of worse.
再等下去那女孩会送命
Another minute, that girl will be dead.
第1小组准备进入 其他各组待命全面攻击
Unit 1, prepare entry. All units stand by for full breach.
回来! 回来!
Get back! Get back!
谈判无效 准备进入
You lost him. Make entry.
贝克认为谈判失败 弗罗斯批准他采取行动
Beck thinks you lost him. Frost gave him the go-ahead.
这不符合程序 奥马尔醉了
That's not the play. Omar's tight.
他有足够时间开枪
He can get a shot off if they breach.
我能继续跟他谈 给我点时间
Look, Nate' I can still talk to him. I just need time.
- 特别行动队 谈判专家需要时间  - 不行 突击队已就位
- HBT 1, negotiator requests time. - Negative. Team's in position.
去他的 我进去
Fuck it. I'm going in.
不 别去 别干傻事 你会多给他一个人质
No. Don't, damn it. Don't pull this shit. You'll give him another hostage.
你有别的办法让他把枪从女孩头上移开?
You know another way to get the gun off the girl's head?
- 谈判专家进入危险区  - 必须让他马上离开
- Negotiator entering kill zone. - You better keep him out.
他会扰乱队员的注意力
Our men will lose objectivity if he's in there.
我是弗罗斯 别进去
This is Frost. Stand down.
- 奥马尔参加过海军陆战队?  - 是的
- Omar Was a Marine, right? - Yeah.
- 有瞄准点吗?  - 卧室 可他离那里太远
- We have a shot? - Bedroom, but he's nowhere near.
他会在射程内 让伊戈尔和巴勒莫瞄准窗口
He will be. Get Eagle and Palermo to that Window.
看我的手势 从背后把他撂倒
Tell them to wait for my signal and put that motherfucker on his back.
赫尔曼 埃伦 阿尔金托
Hellman' Allen, Argento.
我把他引开 你们进去救孩子
When I'm clear, come in there' get that girl.
奥马尔
Yo, Omar.
我接到通知 你妻子到了
Just got word. Your wife's here.
- 妻子? - 闭嘴
- Wife? - Shut the fuck up.
上面派我和你交换人质
I've been authorized to make the trade.
可我要进去看看...
I gotta come in, look around...
...确保没其他人质或别的花招
...make sure there's no other hostages and there's no surprises.
去你的!
Fuck you!
我要先见她
I wanna see her first.
先让我进去 然后我带你妻子来交换孩子
Omar, I gotta come look. Then I can bring in your wife' get the girl, all right?
- 要是你骗我呢?  - 你就打死我!
- What if you're lying? - Then shoot me!
这还差不多
Okay! Fair enough!
慢慢走进来
Nice and slow!
看清楚了 就带我老婆进来 不然要你的命!
You look around, then I get my wife, or you fucking die!
帕勒莫 老鹰 准备狙击
Palermo, Eagle, clear for shot.
- 要行动了 - 就绪
- Okay? Here we go. - Ready.
慢点 你和我没冤没仇...
Move real sloW. This ain't about me or you...
...可我还是会杀了你
...but I'm gonna take you out just the same.
他进去了 现在必须配合他
He's in. We gotta play it out now.
一号单位 原地待命
Unit 1, hold position.
锁门
Lock it.
风和日丽
Nice breeze.
天气不冷 凉爽宜人 适合外出
Great day to be out, you know? Not cold. Cool, kind of brisk.
咱们都待在屋里可惜了
Too bad we got stuck in here.
你都看过了 没花招 开始换人吧
You've seen everything. No surprise. Let's do this.
还要看那些房间 我得确定那里面没别人
I gotta look in those rooms down there. You know, make sure nobody's there.
好吧 走
All right, move.
有球赛?
Football, huh?
是个比赛的好日子
Perfect day for it.
离开海军陆战队后 我没错过一场熊队的主场比赛
I ain't missed a Bears home game since I left the Corps.
当然陆战队是常胜队
Course, the Corps Was a winning team, wasn't it?
你也曾是陆战队员?
Oh' yeah? You were in?
73年去过越南
Yeah. I did a tour in '73.
"永远忠诚" 混蛋 我去过两次 68年69年
Semper fi, motherfucker. I did two tours. '68 and '69.
记得吗? 欢呼时喊
Well' hoo-fucking-rah' Omar.
"呼拉"!
Hoorah!
很少遇到陆战队员 现在人人都加入海军
Don't meet many Marines these days. Everybody joins the Navy.
我看见疑犯
I have a visual on the suspect.
看? 什么也没有 可以开始换人了
See? Nothing here, lieutenant, so now we make the trade.
- 别着急  - 开始数一
- Nuh-uh. Stay cool. - We got a one count.
我说过要检查所有房间
Like I told you, gotta check out everything.
一个水兵和一个陆战队员上厕所撒尿
Omar. A Marine and a sailor are in the bathroom taking a piss.
尿完陆战队员没洗手就走
The Marine goes to leave without Washing up.
水兵说:
Sailor says:
"在海军 上级教我们便后洗手"
"In the Navy' they teach us to wash our hands."
陆战队员转身对他说:
The Marine turns to him and says:
"在陆战队 上级教我们别尿在手上"
"In the Marines, they teach us not to piss on our hands."
- 趴下! - 冲! 冲!
- down! Get down! - Move! Move!
- 疑犯中弹!  - 知道了
- HT's down! - Copy.
你没事吧?
You all right, bud?
没事吧?
Huh? You okay?
没事
Yeah.
- 谢谢 - 分内事
- Thanks. - Sure.
(生日快乐 特拉维斯局长)
过来和我们一起跳 放松
Yeah, boy! Come on. Get down, get funky, get loose!
跳吧 跳吧
Come on! Do it, do it' do it!
你真是难缠
You're a hoedown guy.
我阅人无数
now I've seen everything. Ha-ha-ha.
你看他俩谁跳的最蹩脚?
Okay, which one is the most pathetic out there?
- 你怎么样?  - 不太好
- how you feeling, man? - Not great.
- 我想跟你谈谈就一会  - 好吧
- I wanna talk to you. All right? - All right, cool.
关掉音乐!
Hey! Cut the music!
猜猜看谁又上新闻了
Take a wild guess who's on the news again.
对峙6小时后人质谈判专家丹尼・罗曼冒着生命危险...
After six hours, hostage negotiator Danny Roman risked his own life...
...解除了扣留人质者的武装 结束了对抗
...disarming the hostage-taker to end the standoff.
罗曼中尉 你再次成为英雄
Lieutenant Rornan, looks like you saved the day again.
那是全组努力的结果 我只是跟他周旋
No, it was a team effort. I just talked the guy out.
他有没有说这样做的原因?
Well, did he say anything in there?
他只是想大出风头!
He just wanted to hog the spotlight!
今天我差点让你滚蛋 因为你不听话
I just wanna tell you how close I came to busting your ass because of that shit.
鉴于你不会再犯 这次我不追究
But because it'll never happen again' right, I'll let it go.
他从来只说不做
All right, he's all talk.
说真的那确实需要胆量
Danny, off the record, that was one hell of a gutsy job, man.
再次祝贺你
Again' congratulations.
谢谢局长 生日快乐
Thanks, chief. Congratulations to you.
- 谢谢  - 晚会棒极了
- Thanks. - Great party.
你真参加过海军陆战队?
Were you really in the Marines?
不 我在陆军而且我最讨厌狗
No, I was in the Army and I fucking hate dogs.
尽管今天的结局不错 可你让我的人身陷危险
Despite how things worked out today, you put these guys in jeopardy.
你若成了人质后果将不堪设想
If you were taken hostage, you would've fucked up everything.
所有人都活着 包括你
Everybody lived, Beck. Even you.
好好玩
Play
芝加哥有两万警察 不能轮流吗?
Twenty thousand cops in Chicago. Can't you take turns?
本来打算让内森进去...
I was gonna let Nate go in...
...可我知道琳达会生我气
...but I knew Linda would be pissed at me.
这点内森比你聪明得多
Nate's much smarter than that, right, Nate?
我太聪明 有时聪明反被聪明误
Yeah, I'm too smart. I'm too smart for my own good sometimes.
我要跟你谈谈 有件事很重要
You got a minute? Gotta talk. It's important.
只占你一点时间 我保证就几分钟
Just be a minute, I promise. Just a minute.
去吧 谈你们的秘密
Go on, tell your secrets.
天哪
Man
最近有人主动跟我联系
I was approached by someone recently.
他知道谁偷了伤残基金的钱
He knows who took money from the disability fund.
什么?
What?
- 丢了近200万美元  - 我知道
- Almost 2 million is missing. - Yeah, I know.
据他说 偷钱的人咱们认识 是警察
According to him, we know the guys who took it. Cops.
局里的同事 我们称为朋友的人...
Guys in our own precinct. Guys we might call our friends...
...在偷我们自己的钱
...stealing our own money.
该早些告诉你 可我一直没机会
I would've told you sooner, but this is my first chance.
是谁告诉你的?
Who told you this?
我不能说...
I can't say...
...他知道自己在说什么
...but this guy knows what he's talking about.
74年起就从事这方面工作 一直办这类案子是这方面权威
He's been around' working cases like this. He knows his shit.
他为什么不找内务监察部?
So why didn't he go to Internal Affairs?
因为内务监察部也不干净
Because he thinks Internal Affairs is involved.
他听见尼鲍姆的名字 不知如何是好
He heard Niebaum's name mentioned. He doesn't know what to do.
他们出钱要收买他
They offered to buy him out.
- 结果? - 他说要考虑一下
- And? - And he said he'd think about it.
我们是警校同学 又同在6分局工作过 所以他信任我
We were at the academy' worked Area 6 together, so he trusts me.
可是他...
This guy' uh...
他真的怕得要命
Dan, this guy is really scared.
你什么时候知道这些事的?
When did you find out about all this?
大部份是昨天晚上...
Most of it last night, but I' uh...
可我已调查了两个星期
I've been Working on it for a couple of Weeks now, you know?
你是委员会成员 也许听到消息
I figured that With you on the board you might have heard something.
没有
No.
我什么也没听说
I didn't hear a thing.
他们查过帐 可什么也没发现
Well' they did do an audit' but it didn't prove anything.
若有人偷我们的钱 我们必须找出是谁
If somebody's stealing our money, we gotta find out who.
你把这消息告诉...
You tell this informant...
- 真见鬼  - 我的上帝!
- Oh, shit. - Jesus Christ!
秃头警官!
Officer Bald.
你俩躲在这里干什么? 同性恋?
Are you blowing each other?
你来捣乱坏了我们的好事
About to, till you showed up.
我知道你们搭档的事 可大家都在找你们
I know you're all partners, but everyone's looking for you.
别瞎猜 警官
Don't shine the light in here, officer.
男人不能和搭档拉手?
Can't a guy just hold his partner's hand?
那我就不打扰二位了
I'll let you girls be.
- 把你嘴巴擦干净  - 给我带瓶啤酒过来 大个子
- Wipe that stuff oft your mouth, buddy. - Yeah. Order me a drink, big guy.
天哪
Jesus.
- 咱们再找时间谈吧 - 好的
- We'll finish this later. - Yeah, all right.
别告诉琳达
Yeah. Don't tell Linda.
该死
Shit.
我不想有一天我一个人修房子 丹尼
I don't like the thought of fixing up this house alone, Danny.
可你干这些事...
And with what you're doing...
亲爱的 这是我的工作
Nuh-uh-uh. Darling, that's the job.
问题不在工作
It's not the job.
我能忍受你的工作 可不能忍受你玩命
The job I can deal with. It's how you do the job.
- 就像你今天的行为 - 我没事
- Like what you did today. - I'm fine.
这次没事
This time.
我喜欢你做事有股疯狂劲
What I love about you is that you do these crazy things.
但我要区别疯狂和愚蠢是两码事
It's just that I wish you'd start differentiating betWeen crazy and stupid.
我知道婚姻对你是个新领域...
I know this whole marriage thing is new to you...
...不过每晚回家是其重要组成部份
...but coming home every night is a big part of it.
每晚回家
Every night.
我保证...
Okay. I promise...
...我每天晚上都回家
...I Will come home every night.
无论有多重要的事
No matter what I have to do.
每晚回家
Every night.
你想和谁谈判? 你忘了我知道你的工作就是撒谎
What are you trying to negotiate? You forget that I know you lie for a living.
- 现在不是  - 噢!
- Not right now. - Oh!
听着
Listen' listen.
丹尼・罗曼是有家的男人了
Danny Roman is a married man now.
别再干蠢事了
No more crazy shit, all right?
看见了?
See that?
公共汽车 车沿着大街开走了
That's the bus. The bus is going down the street.
蠢事就在车上
Crazy is on the bus.
什么东西在震动?
What's vibrating' baby?
(11:30弗兰克林公园见内森)
内森在震动
Nate is vibrating.
去吧 代我向内森问好
Go. Tell Nate I said hello.
说我希望他让你远离麻烦
And that I expect him to keep you out of trouble from now on.
(11:30弗兰克林公园见丹尼)
你好吗? 抓到我抽烟了
Hey, how you doing? Caught me. Heh, heh.
丹尼刚呼了我 出了什么事?
Look, Danny beeped me earlier. What's going on?
内森?
Nate?
不许动!
Freeze!
把手举起来!
Get your hands up!
我是警察! 有警员中枪!
Police officer! Officer down!
他说昨晚和告密人谈过
He said he talked to his informant last night.
他的警校同学 6分局的同事
Some guy he was at academy with and knew from Area 6.
这人说他知道退休基金的事
This guy said he knew what Was going down with the pension fund.
告密人没来找你们...
The informant didn't come to you guys...
...是因为他知道内务监察部有人参与
...because he thought someone from Internal Affairs was involved.
我们中的一个?
One of us?
这告密人究竟是谁? 中尉
Exactly who was this informant, lieutenant?
他没说那人的名字
Hey, he didn't tell me his name.
显然有人发现内森根据告密人提供的线索...
It's obvious somebody found out Nate Was investigating the fund...
...在调查基金的事就把他杀了
...off this informant's tip and they took him out.
我们把整件事再从头说一遍
Let's go back to the beginning and do this whole thing again.
我只是发现搭档被人打死
Hey, hey' hey. I just found my partner with his head blown off.
- 我不喜欢被审问!  - 这由不得你
- I don't feel like doing this! - You're gonna have to.
- 见你的鬼去吧!  - 别逼他
- Fuck this! - Back off.
别逼他 尼鲍姆 另找时间谈吧
Back off' Niebaum. We'll do it some other time, okay?
立正!
Order!
我深表惋惜
I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
准备 瞄准 射击
Ready. Aim. Fire.
瞄准 射击
Aim. Fire.
- 是有人敲门吗?  - 你去开
- Is that the door? - Mm. You get it.
该死
Shit.
丹尼 听着 杀死内森的枪找到了
Hey, Danny, listen, they found the gun that killed Nathan.
- 被丢在湖里 没有指纹  - 慢着 他...
- It's in the lake. No fingerprints. - Hang on. He's...
- 我们有搜查令... - 慢着
- I have a search warrant... - Just hold it.
枪上的编号... 是一毒贩被盗3支枪之一
Danny, the serial number on the gun... It was one of three stolen from a dealer.
另两支7个月前被你找到
Two of the guns were recovered by you around seven months ago.
- 记得吗? 第3支枪刚找到  - 你在开玩笑
- The third gun Was not found until now. - You gotta be fucking kidding me.
- 你说真的? - 我们无能为力
- You serious? - Nothing we can do.
听说签发搜查令我们尽快赶来
We came as soon as we heard they were issuing a Warrant.
- 规矩点 他是自己人  - 进来
- Guys, go easy. He's one of ours. - In here. In here.
对不起 凯伦 我们知道这是胡扯
I'm sorry about this' Karen. We all know it's bullshit.
让他们干完就会走的
Just let them do their work and get out.
这是胡扯
It is bullshit.
他站在调查退休基金的警察尸体前 ...
He's standing over a dead cop who Was investigating the fund...
...他有可能得到那把枪 他是基金会委员
...he had access to the gun and he's on the fund's board.
- 有作案动机和机会  - 你是什么人 尼鲍姆?
- He had motive and opportunity. - Who the fuck are you, Niebaum?
内森说告密人曾提到你的名字
It was your name Nate mentioned when he said Internal Affairs was involved.
是我的名字?
now it's my name, huh?
我们也做了些调查 你的名字不断被提及 为什么?
We've got an investigation too, and your name keeps coming up. Wonder why.
也许内森发现你在偷基金的钱
Maybe it's because Nathan found you stealing money from the fund.
督察!
Inspector!
我找到了一些东西
I think I got something in here.
好像是海外帐户
Looks like offshore accounts.
什么...?
What the...?
这不是我的 是你放在这里的
That shit's not mine. You planted this shit.
一会带走
Put it away.
你为什么要陷害我?
Why are you doing this to me, huh?
局长 你不会真的...
Chief, you don't...
中尉 你会被指控...
Lieutenant' do you think you'll be charged...
...杀害勒尼克警官吗?
...with the murder of Officer Roenick?
让一让 请退后
Make a hole here. Come on, come on' back up.
- 让一让! 让他过去! 往后站!  - 别烦他!
- Hey! Give the guy a break! - Get back. Get back.
贝克
Beck.
- 谢谢  - 你还敢在这里露面?
- Thanks. - how can you show your face here?
我早知道你会害死别人
I knew someday you'd get somebody killed.
我们还不知道究竟怎么回事
Nobody really knows what happened, okay?
好了 别这样
Come on, seriously.
怎么回事 丹尼? 我们听到很多说法
What's going on, Danny? We're hearing a lot of shit.
什么?
What?
嘿 丹尼
Hey, Danny.
你进来
Come on inside.
大家继续工作
All right, everybody' get back to work.
坐下 丹尼
Sit down, Danny.
老实说 我不知道该怎么想...
Danny, I'm gonna be honest with you. I don't know what to think...
...但我别无选择...
...but I don't have any choice...
...直到监察部调查结束前
...until this Internal Affairs investigation is complete.
你得交出警徽和枪
So your gun and your badge.
局长
Chief.
你了解我
You know me.
有人陷害我
I'm being set up.
内森说他的告密人知道是谁干的
Nate told me his informant knows who's involved.
帮我找到这告密人 就能真相大白
Help me find this informant' and all this goes away.
是啊
Yeah.
中尉!
Lieutenant!
- 你和勒尼克夫人交谈过吗? - 再问一个问题
- Have you talked to Mrs. Roenick? - One more.
是不是上级要你保持沉默?
Are you allowed to make any comment?
- 琳达 琳达  - 我们走
- Linda. Linda. - We should keep going.
- 不要理她  - 勒尼克夫人 我们走
- No, Karen. - Mrs. Roenick, We should go.
他们对我的指责是无中生有...
Linda, I didn't do what they say I did. L...
- 勒尼克夫人 我们走  - 混蛋 丹尼
- Mrs. Roenick, We should go. - Fuck you' Danny.
混蛋 尼鲍姆 你们都是混蛋 是你们杀了他
Fuck Niebaum. Fuck all of you. You all killed him.
别站在我面前
Don't you stand here. Don't you stand here in my face.
别再跟我说一个字
Don't say one more fucking word to me.
你让我失去了他
You took him away from me.
求上帝饶恕你 你让杰瑞米失去父亲
God help you, Danny. You took him away from Jeremy.
你站在这里...你会内疚终生
now you stand here... You stand here and you just live with that.
勒尼克夫人 别这样 我们走吧
Mrs. Roenick. Please, let's go home.
丹尼 该走了
Danny, we need to go.
我们走吧 跟我来
We need to go. Come on, this way.
在你家里找到的文件:
The papers found in your house:
你要解释清楚 怎么会在海外有一大笔钱?
Can you come up With an explanation as to why you had that kind of money?
你不能证明那钱和基金有关...
You have no proof the money had to do with the fund...
...或是罗曼先生有海外帐户
...or that Mr. Roman even opened those accounts.
那笔钱洗得很干净...
The money in them was Well-laundered...
...最后一笔与基金被盗数目相同
...but the last deposit matched the last amount stolen from the fund.
我没有任何海外帐户
I don't have any offshore accounts.
银行对帐单在你家里 你站在尸体旁
The statements Were in your home. You were standing over the body.
你在起诉我的委托人? 那全是间接证据
Are you charging my client? Because all of this is circumstantial.
有支枪与你有关...
We have a gun linked to you...
...还有水里捞出的手套
...and a pair of gloves that We took from the water.
能解释他手上为何没残留火药
Which explains why your client had no powder on his hands.
市民对腐败警察深恶痛绝
You know how this city feels about corrupt cops.
我闭着眼也能定你的罪
I'll get a conviction with my eyes closed.
说出其余钱在哪里 还有谁是你同伙...
Just tell us where the rest of the money went, who your partners were and maybe...
- 也许...  - 我要和我的委托人谈谈
- Maybe... - I need to speak to my client.
给你一天时间达成认罪协议
I'll give you one day to make a deal.
听见没有? 一天
You hear me? One day.
之后将没有条件可谈
After that, there'll be no deal to negotiate.
我们逮捕你 你面临最高刑期 我亲自办
We will arrest you and you will face the maximum penalty. I'll see to it.
明天带着你的决定来
Be here tomorrow and have a decision made.
丹尼 丹尼
Danny. Danny.
丹尼
Danny.
- 丹尼  - 干什么?
- Danny. - What?
他们会起诉 陪审团会判你有罪
Understand that they have a case that a jury will convict on.
我没有其他办法
I can't do any more for you.
认罪争取减刑
Cut a deal.
凯伦
Karen.
到车上等我 别担心
Go and wait for me in the car. Don't worry.
不会有事的
Everything's gonna be fine.
- 千万不要做蠢事  - 蠢事?
- Danny, please don't do anything crazy. - Crazy? Heh.
蠢事坐公共汽车走了 记得吗?
Crazy's on the bus, remember?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我就来
Be right back.
(芝加哥市建于1837年3月4日)
(内务监察部)
- 丹尼・罗曼 - 我要见尼鲍姆
- Danny Roman - I'm going to see Niebaum.
先生 请等候 我通知他
Sir' could you wait just a minute? I have to buzz him' sir.
罗曼先生 等等!
Mr. Roman, Wait, sir!
再清楚地说一遍... 再清楚地说一遍
You made it clear... Make it clear again.
这也太...
Come on. This is...
等等 等等 找我有什么事?
Hold on. Hold on. Roman. What can I do for you?
谁都有权见指控他的人 是吧 检察官大人?
Man's got a right to face his accusers, doesn't he, inspector?
- 我要跟你谈谈 - 你说吧
- We need to talk. - Go ahead, talk.
我要知道是怎么回事
I wanna know what's going on.
你杀了你的搭档 除非有变你将被正式起诉
You killed your partner and you're about to be formally indicted for it.
你没有回答我的问题
You're not answering my question.
内森说你也有份 我要知道
Nate told me you were involved. I wanna know how.
看着我的眼睛 说你没干
Look me in the eye and tell me you weren't involved.
- 看着我的眼睛! - 看着你的眼睛干什么?
- Look me in the eye! - Look you in the eye for What?
你把这故事讲给法官听
Lookit' why don't you tell it to the judge?
我们谈完了 叫他出去
All right? We're finished. Get him out of here.
- 你不能这样做 - 混蛋!
- You're not doing this! - Look, you. Go!
罗曼
Roman.
不!
No!
操
Aah! Fuck.
锁门 锁上!
Lock the door. Lock it!
不要错上加错
Don't make things worse than they already are.
- 快把枪放下 - 坐下
- Just put the gun down now. - You, sit your ass down.
- 坐下! - 我听你的
- Sit! - Okay, man, you got it.
这关系到我的一生
This is my life here' Niebaum.
- 告诉我答案  - 我没有答案给你
- I want some answers. - I don't have any answers.
把枪放下 快出去!
Put the gun down and leave.
你不想说? 不说谁也别想走!
You don't feel like talking? We're gonna stay here until you do.
你看着办...
It's your choice...
...因为今天我不想进监狱
...because I'm not going to jail today.
走!
Move!
走! 走!
Go! Go!
- 好的  - 别磨蹭!
- All right. - Come on!
把枪放下
Drop your weapon.
- 放下枪 丹尼  - 放下枪
- Drop it' Danny. - Guns down.
- 放下武器!  - 放下!
- Drop the weapon. - Drop it.
这只是警告! 下一枪将打在你头上
That wasn't an accident. And neither will the next one that goes in your head.
下来! 快点!
now get down here, now. Come on!
所有人到桌子那边去
All right, everybody in here march over to that desk over there.
把枪 手铐 钥匙 所有东西...
Put your guns, cuffs, keys, everything...
...放在桌子上 赶快出去! 动作快点! 快走!
...on this desk and get out of here. Let's go. Move! Move it!
丹尼
Danny.
- 你来干什么?  - 全城警察都听到了通知
- What are you doing here? - The call's out on the city-wide.
- 我这是被他们逼的 - 丹尼 你才结婚
- See What they're making me do? - Danny, you just got married, man.
替凯伦想想!
Think about Karen.
我是在替凯伦着想
I am thinking about Karen.
考虑到这点我很高兴你来了
And now that I think about it, I'm glad you're here.
你提高了赌注
You just raised the ante.
- 你也过来  - 丹尼 你疯了
- Join the party. - God, Danny, this is crazy.
拿出你的枪放在桌子上!
Take your guns off. Put them on this table now!
你知道我说的是两支
I know you heard me say both of them.
丹尼 听我说 现在罢手还不晚
Danny, listen to me. It's not too late to stop this.
你就是想说服我放弃?
You trying to talk me down? That it?
这很不理智 解决不了问题
Danny, this is crazy. This isn't helping you.
- 我和他与这件事无关  - 没错
- Me and him have nothing to do With this. - Right.
我们相识20年 你要干什么?
I've known you 20 years. What are you doing?
我让你留下来 可你不能发号施令
I know I made you stay' Frost, but you cannot monopolize the conversation.
现在这里的指挥不是你 是我
You're not the scene commander here. I am. You.
你是尼鲍姆的秘书? 叫什么名字?
You're Niebaum's secretary, right? What's your name?
我叫麦琪 是他的助理
My name's Maggie, and I'm his assistant.
你别害怕
Maggie, don't be scared.
这种局面我经历过很多
I'm somewhat familiar with situations like this, all right?
我不怕 我遇上过两次抢劫 有一次被枪指着
I'm not scared. I've been mugged tWice, once at gunpoint.
我见过枪...
Guns are not new to me...
...可若有机会 我宁愿避开枪
...but I'd rather avoid them if I get the chance.
我想这次你没有机会
Well' I don't think you're gonna have that chance this time, Maggie.
你是尼鲍姆的助手 你和这件事有很大关系
And if you're Niebaum's assistant' you have everything to do With this.
我没有 我不是这头猪的手下
But not me' bro. Okay? I don't work for this pig.
- 我不是警察 - 我知道你是鲁迪・狄蒙斯
- I'm not a cop. - You're Rudy Timmons.
为小人工作的小人 不认识我了?
You're a rat for the rat squad. You don't remember me?
你92年因信用卡诈骗被我逮捕
I arrested you in '92 for credit-card fraud.
对 我想起来了
Oh' shit. Yeah, wow. Yeah, I remember you.
我记得你
I remember you. Hey' man!
上次见面 你是穿蓝制服的瘦小伙
Last time I saw you, you were a clean-cut boy in blue.
- 你出什么事了?  - 这正是我要搞明白的 鲁迪
- What happened to you' man? - That's what We're here to find out, Rudy.
一号机 已经到达现场
Air 1 ' realize the location.
不知他们在不在外面
I wonder if they're out there.
你的同伙 尼鲍姆
Your partners' Niebaum.
真正的罪犯
The guilty ones.
我要找的人
My guys.
他们快来了
They'll come' you know.
怕我让你说出真相一定要阻止我
Scared shitless I'll get the truth out of you and try and stop them.
他们若杀不了我 就会杀死你
And if they can't get me' they'll kill you.
该死 叫他们拉警戒线疏散人群
Goddamn it. Have them clear the perimeter and start evac.
河上船只马上离开!
I don't want anything moving on that fucking river!
找出电话总线 关闭电梯
Locate the phone panel. Lock down the elevator.
清理楼梯 派第2小组守住监察部门口
Have these guys clear the stairWell. Have Unit 2 hold outside Internal Affairs.
跟我来
You got it. Come on.
天哪 记者已经到了
Christ, they're here already.
把指挥部设在船上躲开媒体
Set up command on that barge over there so the press can't get to us.
情况怎么样?
What do you got?
20层以下电梯都锁上了
We locked down the elevators from the 20th floor down.
贝克 窃听电话线路
Beck. Let's get the phones hooked up.
我很担心
I got a real concern.
他了解我们的策略 要封锁的地方很多
He knows our tactics and we got a lot of real estate to lock down.
人手够吗?
Do we have the manpoWer?
6个分局派了人支援...
We got personnel from six different districts...
...他仍会设法控制局面
...but he's still gonna try and control the environment.
等着瞧这回谁赢
We'll just see who wins the race.
罪犯是神枪手
Perpetrator is an expert marksman.
战略专家 精通炸药
He's an expert in explosives and tactics.
大家不得轻举妄动 提高警惕
Gentlemen, play this by the numbers.
随时准备开枪
Maintain your fields of fire.
电梯
Elevators.
那边是罗曼
Fucking Roman's up there, man.
他劫持了弗罗斯
He's got Frost inside.
找机会一枪打死他
See a chance to end this, we take him out.
我们是瞎子 他看得一清二楚
We're blind and he's seeing 20-20.
- 特工?  - 是的
- Intel? - Yeah.
打开19-21层的监视监听系统
I want visuals and audio set up from 19 and 21.
- 是 长官 - 法利 你和他谈判
- Yes, sir. - Farley, you're negotiating.
- 他能吃了法利  - 局长...
- He'll eat Farley up. - Commander, uh...
...你要是想跟他谈...  - 你要不能解决他 我自己来
...if you Wanna talk to him... - You can't handle it, I won't have a choice.
先把他锁定! 同时给他打电话
Get him locked down first. In the meantime' Farley, get on the fucking phone.
- 去找大楼工程师  - 马上搞定
- Someone locate the building engineer. - Right away.
天哪
Oh' boy.
特拉维斯局长
Chief Travis.
我是特工格瑞 他是莫兰
Special Agents Grey, this is Moran.
我们是联邦调查局谈判专家
We're the FBI negotiators.
政府大楼是我们的管辖区
It's a federal building. It's our jurisdiction.
他是我们的人 由我们处理
He's one of ours. We got this.
我们暂时先不插手
Fine With us. For now.
我们有眼睛了
Chief. We got eyes.
臭小子! 2号探头
Son of a bitch. Go to Camera 2.
6个都被他发现了
He got all six. We got nothing.
我们必须看到里面
We gotta see in that room.
没眼睛 没耳朵 看来我们没别的办法
No eyes, no ears. Looks like we're running out of options.
- 现在情况怎样?  - 更新报道
- I want status reports now. - Give me an update.
报告情况
Give me status.
报告情况 你们看见什么?
Somebody give me status. Tell me what you see.
全部通道已被封锁
All shafts are locked down, sir.
窗户全被遮挡住
Blinds closed.
视线为零
Visibility's zero, sir.
他被包围了
We contained him.
我们没包围他 他把自己封住
We have not contained him. He's contained himself.
将我们挡在门外
He's cut us off.
再打电话 问他想怎么样
Try the phone again. See what he wants.
说话
Talk.
喂?
Hello?
Yeah. Hello?
我是鲁迪 别杀我 我不是他
I'm Rudy, so don't shoot me thinking I'm him. Please.
鲁迪 我是法利
Rudy, my name is Farley.
- 叫丹尼接电话行吗?  - 法利要跟你谈谈
- Could you please get Danny on the line? - Farley would like to talk to you.
告诉他我只和克瑞斯・塞比安谈
Tell him I only wanna talk to Chris Sabian.
他只和克瑞斯・塞比安谈
He'll only talk to, uh, Chris Sabian.
20分钟内塞比安不来 你死
Tell him if Sabian's not here in 20 minutes' you die.
除克瑞斯・塞比安 我不和别人谈
I don't wanna talk to anyone else but Chris Sabian.
好的
Okay.
我们听见了
We heard you.
他们说听见了
He said they heard you.
克瑞斯・塞比安是谁?
Who's Chris Sabian?
- 听说过这名字 - 西区分局的
- I heard that name before. - He's from the west side.
曾连续谈判55小时 从不使用武力战术
Once he talked 55 hours. Never forces tactical action.
不知丹尼怎么认识他的
I don't know how Danny knows him.
- 找到塞比安  - 打911找克瑞斯・塞比安
- So find Sabian. - 911 Chris Sabian.
说话
Come on.
跟我谈谈
Talk to me.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
哪里也不去 求你出来吧
I'm not going anywhere' so please come out.
你不想让我出去 因为我现在想杀了她
You don't want me to come out. I wanna kill her.
我想让你出来...
I do want you to come out. Come out...
...咱们可以谈谈
...so we can discuss this.
你根本没在听我说
You're not even listening to me.
我当然在听
Yes, I am listening to you.
你答应了要出来 出来吧
I just... You promised that you'd come out, so come on out' all right?
我不想隔着门说话
I don't wanna do this through the door.
我想心平气和地解决问题
Look, I just wanna do something without arguing, okay?
让我们的生活回归轨道
Let's get on the road.
- 你的衣服很合身  - 不
- Your clothes look fine. - No.
- 真的很好 - 可有人说...
- They do. - According to some people...
...我穿滑雪服显得很臃肿
...I look fat in ski clothes.
这不是她用的词 她说的...
That's not the word she used. She used...
...比这更难听
...a much worse word.
宝贝 挂上电话!
Honey' get off the phone!
- 挂上电话  - 我知道
- Get off the phone. - I know.
- 挂上电话  - 不
- Get off the phone. - No.
我是你爸爸 现在我对你很生气
I'm your father and I'm very upset with you right now.
试试新毛衣
Try your sweater.
宝贝 挂上电话
Honey' but get off the phone.
我要你向妈妈道歉...
I want you to apologize...
...因为你说她像...
...to your mother for saying she looks...
..."肥婆"
..."wide."
这词不好 肥婆
That's not a good Word to use, wide.
你愿意别人叫你肥婆?
how'd you like to be called wide?
听见了? 我是认真的
You hear me? I'm very serious.
我很生气!
I'm very angry with you!
马上挂上电话! 挂上电话
Right now. Get off the phone. Get off the phone.
- 不 - 别逼我...
- No. - Don't you make me...
嘘
Shh.
我说服过要炸掉希尔斯大厦的人...
I talked a man out of blowing up the Sears Tower...
...却无法让妻子走出卧室 让女儿挂上电话
...but I can't talk my wife out of a bedroom or my kid off a phone.
因为没有举着枪的人站在你身后
That's because no one's standing behind you with a big gun.
对 我保留意见
Yeah, well, that's debatable.
等一下
Hold on.
喂?
Hello?
对 他在家
Yeah. He's right here.
找你的
It's for you.
喂?
Hello?
塞比安20分钟赶到
Sabian's 20 minutes out.
只剩15分钟
And we only got 15.
再给丹尼打电话 让他推迟期限
All right, call Danny and change that deadline.
告诉他塞比安正往这里赶
Tell him Sabian's on his way.
塞比安?
Sabian?
我是法利
No, it's, um, Farley.
法利 我说过 我只跟克瑞斯・塞比安谈
Look, Farley, I told you, I don't wanna talk to anyone but Chris Sabian.
他在来的路上
Yeah, uh, he's on his way, okay?
他很快就到 多给我们一点时间
He's gonna be here real soon. We just need more time.
你们没有时间了
You don't have more time, Farley.
丹尼 拜托 告诉我
Danny, please, tell me.
你这是干什么? 这事闹得很严重
What are you doing here, okay? This is pretty serious.
这事当然很严重 你们最好认真对待
You're goddamn right! So why don't you take me seriously?
是的 我们只是...
Well' we are. We are. We just' um...
- 我只想和你谈谈 - 等等
- It just, um... I just want to talk to you. - Wait, wait.
等等 你以为你能说服我 法利?
Wait, Wait. You think you can talk me down, Farley?
听我说 我需要...
Look, um, I need to, um...
告诉我你想要什么?
Tell me what you want, all right?
好的 法利
Okay, Farley.
你想试试? 我给你个机会
You want a shot? I'll give you a shot.
塞比安到达前还有时间
Yeah. We got some time before Sabian gets here.
我想要什么? 让我想想 这样吧... 能让我见牧师吗?
Oh. What do I want? Um, let's see. how about... Can I see a priest?
不 你不能见牧师
No, you can't see a priest.
很好 法利 你不应该让我见牧师
That's good, Farley. Good. You shouldn't let me see a priest.
牧师让人联想到死亡 此刻你不愿让我想到死
A priest is associated With death, and you don't want me thinking about death.
不 不
No, no.
可你刚才说"不" 你不能说"不"
But you told me "no." You can't say "no."
解救人质时永远不要说"不"
Never use "no" in a hostage situation.
- 放松点  - 我很放松!
- Would you relax? - I'm very fucking relaxed!
让我给你点忠告:
But let me give you some adNice:
对挟持人质的人不要说"不" 手册上有
Never say "no" to a hostage-taker. It's in the manual.
- 你还要对我说"不"吗?  - 不 我不说
- now, are you gonna tell me "no" again? - No, I'm not.
答错了 把"不"字从你的字典上抹掉
Wrong answer! Eliminate "no" from your vocabulary.
永远不要说"不" "不行" "不可以"
Never use "no," "don't," "won't" or "can't," all right?
这样说堵死退路 留下唯一选择...
It eliminates options. The only option that leaves...
...是杀掉人质 懂吗?
...is to shoot someone. Understand?
- 是的 - 很好 说"是"就对了
- Uh, yes. Yes, I do. - Yes! Good! See, "yes" is good.
再说"不" 我就要杀人了 练习一遍
Say "no" again, I'll kill somebody, all right? now, let's practice.
我能见牧师吗?
Can I see a priest?
我们能不能谈谈这件事...
Uh, let's not... You know what? Can We just talk...
如你所愿 咱们正在谈! 我能见牧师吗?
You wanted to talk. We are talking. now, can I see a priest?
让我想想办法
Uh, I'll see what I can do.
很好 你学得很快
That's good, Farley. now you're learning.
我要支冲锋枪 将人质都杀死
I'd like a submachine gun, so I can blow everyone away.
- 让我研究一下  - 干得不错 法利
- I'll look into that. - Good. uou're doing good, Farley.
你有没有对太太不忠?
You ever cheat on your wife?
- 不 - 小心 我要杀人了
- No. - Watch yourself. I'll kill someone.
你有没有对太太不忠? 回答我!
You ever cheat on your wife? Answer!
让我研究一下
I'll see what I can do.
我得想个好办法
I'll haVe to think about that. Um, I'll look into that.
你有没有...
You ever, um...
...扮成女生让别人打你屁股?
...dress up like a schoolgirl and get you ass spanked?
丹尼 听着 我只是想跟你谈谈
Danny, look, okay, all right, all I wanna do is talk to you.
我正在跟你谈 你有没有...
I am talking! now, did you or did you not...
...扮女生让别人打你屁股?
...ever dress up like a schoolgirl and get your ass spanked?
- 这事我得查一下  - 天啊 丹尼
- Have to look into that, Danny. - Jesus, Farley.
没有法律规定你不能男扮女装 可我以前真不了解你
Nothing against you dressing up like a girl, but I didn't know that about you, Farley.
- 这样做不能解决问题  - 不解决问题?
- Danny, this is really unproductive. - Unproductive?
你说的对
You're right. It is.
给我讲个笑话 你会讲笑话吗?
So tell me a joke, Farley. You know any jokes?
- 不 我...  - 不?
- No. - No?
你断送一条人命 法利 游戏结束!
You just cost someone their life, Farley! Game over!
开枪了
Shot fired.
开枪了 开枪了 看见什么了?
Shot fired. Shot fired. Can anyone see?
别让他挂电话
Don't let him go.
你不能说服我! 不能让我延长期限!
You can't talk me down! You can't make me change the deadline!
快找塞比安!
now get me Sabian!
你们还有6分42秒 41...
You got six minutes, 42, 41...
- 40! - 丹尼 有人受伤吗?
- Forty! - Listen, Danny, is anybody hurt?
有人受伤吗?
Is anybody hurt?
我们没事 别再说不了 蠢货!
We're okay. Just don't be saying "no" no more, motherfucker!
该死!
Oh' fuck.
- 保持镇静 - 对不起 我很抱歉
- Everybody calm down. - I'm so sorry. No, I'm so sorry.
我非常抱歉
I'm so fucking sorry.
报告情况
Give me status.
告诉我你们看见什么
Somebody give me status. Tell me what you see.
能见度零
Visibility zero, sir.
几分钟前...
Just a few moments ago...
...市府大楼内一声枪响
...a single shot was fired inside the city administration building.
我们在下面听不见...
We, of course, could not hear it down here...
全芝加哥都在看着我们
We got the whole city of Chicago watching this.
这会成为警方的噩梦
This could turn into a press nightmare.
万一塞比安到不了怎么办?
What do we do if Sabian can't make it?
别忘了上面是丹尼・罗曼
We gotta remember that that's Danny Roman upstairs.
我们和他共事12年 还不知道他究竟干了什么
We've worked with the guy for 12 years and don't really know what he's done.
知道他正在干什么
We know what he's doing now.
我不希望掺杂个人情绪
I don't want this to get personal for us.
他显然已经... 别偷听
He's obviously over... Hey, do you mind?
他显然已经疯了
He's obviously gone over the edge.
这与交情无关
This is not personal.
若派人冲进去 会给更多人带来危险...
If I thought sending these guys, my team in would put more people in jeopardy...
...我不会同意
...I Wouldn't consider it.
我也不想冲进去 可这是唯一的办法
I don't wanna go in there, but it's our best option.
没人能说服他
He can't be talked down.
会来人救我们出去 别担心丹尼
They'll get us out. Don't worry about Danny.
- 他不会伤害任何人  - 胡说
- He's not gonna hurt anybody. - Bullshit.
谁知道这疯子要干什么
No one knows what this crazy fucker is gonna do.
这事与我和麦琪无关
This has nothing to do with me and Maggie.
你和他老交情了 你让他放了我们
You know, you're his friend. You get him to let us go.
你习惯了奴役的镣铐...
Because once you familiarize yourself with the chains of bondage...
...就会主动向它伸出四肢
...you prepare your own limbs to wear them.
亚伯拉罕・林肯说的 我信
Fucking Abraham Lincoln said that and I believe it.
你必须让他马上放了我们!
So you have gotta get me the fuck out! now!
鲁迪 闭嘴 我们能处理
Do yourself a favor and keep quiet. We'll handle this.
别告诉我闭嘴 别告诉我你能处理...
Don't tell me to be quiet and don't tell me you can fucking handle it...
...你们谁也没经历过这场面
...because none of you ever been in a situation like this before.
- 你给我闭上嘴  - 去你妈的!
- Just shut the fuck up. - Fuck you!
- 鸟人  - 别吵了
- Prick. - All right, that's enough.
他在外面能听见 枪在他手里 所以得听他的
He's gonna hear you out there, and he's got the gun' so he's in charge.
你们都小点声
Both of you need to pipe down.
丹尼 放麦琪走 她与此事无关
Danny. I think you should let Maggie go. She's not involved.
她是女人 别把她扯进来...
She's a woman, and it's only fair...
别因为我是女人放我 我讨厌这理由
I didn't ask to be let go because I'm a woman. I hate that crap.
我和他应该走 我们与此事无关
Me and him should be let go because we had nothing to do with this.
- 这是你们警察之间的事  - 跟我们没一点关系
- It's between you cops. - We have nothing to do with this.
丹尼 听着 我已不是街头...
Danny, Danny, look' I'm not some just dirt merchant...
...卖假情报的混混了
...loose in the street anymore.
我不是 我有了不错的新女友 我想回去
I'm not. I got a nice new lady friend that I would like to get back to.
她有个孩子 是个好孩子
And she has got this kid, Albert. Ah, super kid, Dan.
- 他很棒  - 你还能怎么样?
- Great kid. - Dan, what do you think you can do?
看看电视
Take a look at that screen.
他们认为你是杀人犯 会设法干掉你
They think you're a killer, Danny. They're gonna try to take you out.
塞比安能做什么? 他无法阻止他们
What do you think Sabian can do? He can't do anything to stop this.
你呢 弗罗斯?
What about you' Frosty?
你也认为我是杀人犯?
You think I'm a killer too, huh?
拜托
Come on.
你认识我20年了
You've known me for 20 years.
你认为内森是我杀的?
You think I killed Nate?
我不知道 丹尼
I don't know what to think, Danny.
我要告诉你 丹尼小子:
I'll tell you this' Danny boy:
你这样做于事无补
What you're doing is not helping.
嘿 学生妹
Hey, schoolgirl.
还在为刚才差劲的表现沮丧?
You still sweating that ugly display you gave us all a few minutes ago?
别再抵毁自己了 我们都有过糟糕的日子
Stop kicking yourself in the ass. We all have our bad days. Beck.
贝克 别想攻进来 我的防守很坚固
Stop trying to figure out how to get in here. L'm well bunkered.
巴勒莫 嘴里别叨着牙签
Palermo, take that toothpick out of your mouth.
万一有情况 我不想你把它吞下去
Wouldn't want you to swallow it if something goes down.
好了 伙计们...
That's right, sports fans...
...是我 丹尼・罗曼
...it's me, Danny Roman.
我在楼上
The man upstairs.
戏开幕前想和大家打个招呼
Just wanted to say hello before the curtain goes up on this little drama.
你们都想知道为什么来这里
I guess you're all wondering why we're here.
很简单
Well' it's simple.
我们要查出谁偷了我们的钱...
We're here to find out who took our money...
...谁杀害了内森 因为不是我干的
...and who killed Nate' because it Wasn't me.
我们中出了坏警察...
There's some bad cops among us...
...今天我们要查出是谁
...and today we're gonna find out who they are.
我知道你们不信
now, I know how that sounds.
知道你们在想:
I know what you're thinking:
"他疯了 他是凶手"
"He's gone. He's a murderer."
可我还是那个与你们生死与共的臭小子...
But I'm that same son of a bitch you trusted your lives With...
...一起打球 一起喝酒
...played softball with, went drinking with.
还是那个你邀请回家庆祝儿子洗礼的人 唐瑞
I'm the same guy you invited to your house to celebrate your kid's baptism, Tonray.
还是那个在体育场...
The same guy who saved Palermo's ass...
...从狙击手枪下救过巴勒莫一命的人
...when that sniper had a bead on him at the stadium gig.
好极了
This is good, huh?
丹尼想激起我们同情 好让我们下不了手
Danny,s trying to get us to Stockholm so we think twice about taking him out.
现在我要...
now, I want...
我需要你们大家...
No, I need you guys...
...明白我别无选择
...to understand that I had no choice here.
我的生活被剥夺
My life was being stripped away from me.
先是他们杀了内森
First, they kill Nate.
后来收走我的警徽
Then they took my badge.
现在是你们
Then you guys.
下一步...
Next...
...他们要送我进监狱 让我失去妻子
...they were gonna take away my wife by sending me to prison.
这回...
And that...
...我忍无可忍
...I cannot take.
没她我活不下去...
I can't live without...
你们设身处地想想
Put yourself in my position.
我还能怎么办?
What else could I do?
通知队员改用第3频道
Get word out to our team. We're switching to frequency three.
- 是  - 快点办
- Yes, sir. - Run.
我想告诉大家我被陷害 可没人愿意听
I tried to tell everyone I Was being set up' but no one wanted to listen.
现在由不得你们
Well, now you have no choice.
你们必须听 因为我们要待在这里...
You got to listen, because we're not leaving here...
...直到查出陷害我的人
...until I find out who set me up.
我警告你们:
Let me warn you:
杀害内森的凶手担心尼鲍姆知道底细
Whoever killed Nate is frightened that Niebaum might know something.
他们想尽快了结此事
They're going to try and end this quickly.
另一个警告:
Another Warning:
我知道交战原则 所以别试探我
I know the rules of engagement, so don't test me.
你们还有4分钟让塞比安赶到...
You got four minutes to get Sabian here...
...否则就会知道我不是虚张声势
...or you'll find out just how serious I really am.
看着我的眼睛告诉我 尼鲍姆
I want you to look me in the eye' Niebaum.
看着我
Right here.
告诉我...
now, tell me...
...你何时发现内森在调查基金?
...when did you find out Nate was investigating the fund?
我第一次发现内森在调查是...
I first found that Nathan was conducting the investigation...
...跟你谈过话后 他遇害后
...after I spoke with you after he was killed.
你撒谎 我知道你撒谎
You're lying. And I know you're lying.
你知道? 你能看透我想什么? 罗曼
Oh' you know it, huh? You can read my mind, Roman, is that it?
我不会读心 但我会看你的眼睛
No, I'm not. I'm reading your eyes.
眼睛不会撒谎
The eyes can't lie.
不知道我是干哪行的吗?
Didn't you know what I was doing?
我教你识别谎言的方法 真正的警察...
A quick lesson in lying. See' this is what us real cops do.
研究撒谎的人
We study liars.
例如:
Example:
我若问你视觉类问题 如你最喜欢的颜色...
If I ask you a question about something visual, like your favorite color...
...你的眼睛会向上看左边...
...and your eyes go up and to the left...
...神经生理学家说眼睛转向那方向...
...neurophysiology tells us that your eyes go that in that direction...
...因为你在进入视觉皮层
...because you're accessing the visual cortex.
因此你说的是实话
Therefore, you're telling the truth.
如果眼睛向上看右边...
If your eyes go up and right...
表示你进入大脑想像中心...
...you access the creative centers of the brain...
...我们知道你在胡扯
...and We know you're full of shit.
再试一次
now, let's try this again.
你最喜欢的电视节目?
What's your favorite television show?
我不跟你玩这种愚蠢的游戏 罗曼
I'm not gonna play your stupid fucking game, okay, Roman?
为什么? 害怕我们揭穿你撒谎?
Oh' why, Niebaum? You afraid We'll catch you in a lie?
你什么时候发现内森调查基金?
When did you find out Nate Was investigating the fund?
- 和你谈过以后  - 他在撒谎 鬼也看得出!
- Ahem. After I spoke with you. - That is a fucking lie if I've ever seen one!
- 去你的 我根本没眨眼睛 - 不用眨眼睛
- Fuck you! I never blinked my eyes! - You didn't have to blink.
你的肢体语言表明你有撒谎
Your body language says you're lying.
他紧张 你还想要他怎样?
He's nervous, Danny. What do you expect?
闭嘴 你知道这很灵!
Shut up' Frost! You know how this works!
不只眼睛 还有别的
It's not just your eyes, Niebaum. It's everything.
咳嗽 打喷嚏 交叉腿 挠屁股...
If you cough, sneeze, uh, cross your legs, scratch your ass...
...都是提示 你骗不了人
...they're all telltale signs. You can't cheat.
你可以用那死鱼眼瞪我
You can stare at me with those dead-ass eyes of yours all you want.
可你违背不了规律
You can't beat the system.
最后一个问题:
One last question:
是谁杀了内森?
Do you know who killed Nate?
是你
You.
我看不出来 上 下 左 右...
I don't know. I couldn't tell. Up, down, right, left...
下面是什么? 扑克戏法?
So, What now? Card tricks?
闭嘴!
Shut the fuck up, Niebaum!
你知道内森在调查基金就杀了他
You knew Nate Was investigating the fund and you killed him.
你能结束这一切 可你大概不愿意
You could've ended this, but I guess you don't Want to.
这太糟了
That's too bad.
真的很糟糕 鲁迪...
That's really too bad, Rudy...
...因为丹尼・罗曼开始喜欢你了
...because Danny Roman was just starting to like you.
叫丹尼・罗曼等一下
Well' tell Danny Roman to hold the fuck on.
丹尼
Danny.
- 丹尼 你不想这么做  - 你怎么知道?
- Danny, you don't wanna do this. - how do you know?
你真认为我能杀内森 怎么知道我不想这么做?
If you think I could kill Nate, how the fuck do you know I don't wanna do this?
- 谁? - 丹尼・罗曼?
- Yeah? - Danny Roman?
我是克瑞斯・塞比安
This is Chris Sabian here.
来得正好 你来得很及时
Ah, good timing, Chris. You made it just in time.
- 我运气不错 没堵车  - 很高兴你接受我的邀请
- Well, I got lucky. Traffic was light. - Glad you accepted my invitation.
说什么我也不能错过 有两年没见了?
I wouldn't have missed it for the world. What's it been' Danny? Two years?
自从那次两个组在北区碰上后
Not since both our teams showed up for that gig on the north side.
你的级别高把我们赶走了
You pulled rank and ran my boys out of there.
两个谈判专家在一起没法干
Two negotiators on the same site never work.
那这算什么? 更正谬论的一个例外?
So, What's this, then? The, uh, exception that disproves the rule?
你干好你的活 我干好我的...
Look, you do your job' I do mine...
...也许我们都能活着出去
...maybe we both walk out in one piece.
- 问你一个关键问题  - 为什么要找你?
- Here's the million-dollar question. - Why you?
没错
Exactly.
我有我的原因 现在不想说
I got my reasons. I don't wanna go into them now.
以后会告诉你
We'll talk about that later.
这是初次约会 我不想失礼
This is our first date, Chris. The courting period.
劝说我这种人无效时 你会干些什么?
So, What do guys like you do when you're not talking guys like me down?
我是个很顾家的人 通常会和家人待在一起
Well' I, uh... I'm a homebody, Danny. I spend a lot of time with my family.
我的孩子
My' um, kid.
我看很多书
I, uh, read a lot of books.
还看了很多老电影 电影频道
I, um, watch a lot of old movies. AMC.
你有卫星天线吗? 他们播放很多西部片
You got a satellite? They show all those old, uh, Westerns.
西部片?
Westerns? Heh.
我喜欢看喜剧片
I like comedies, myself.
不过我喜欢"原野奇侠" 那是部好电影
I did like Shane though. That's a good one.
"原野奇侠" 那是部好电影...
Uh, Shane. now, that's a good one...
...可我更喜欢英雄活到最后的电影
...but, uh, I'd have picked one where the hero lives at the end' you know?
例如"好汉利奥"或"红河"
Like, uh, Rio Bravo or Red River.
你记错了
You're talking about the wrong movie.
西恩没死 最后他骑马离去 那个孩子 布兰顿...
Shane lives. At the end of it, he's riding oft and that kid, uh, Brandon...
德怀尔
De Wilde.
对 布兰顿・德怀尔喊: "西恩 回来 西恩"
Brandon's De Wilde's calling his name: "Shane, come back! Shane!"
对不起 我得告诉你西恩死了
I'm sorry to tell you this, but Shane died.
你没看见西恩死 那是个假设
You never see Shane dead. That's an assumption.
这是个普遍错误
It's a common mistake.
最后一个镜头 能看见他从马上跌落
You see, in the final shot, you see him slumped over his horse.
他没有回头看 因为他做不到 西恩死了
He doesn't look back' because he's can't. Shane's dead.
他落马因为中弹 落马不表示他死了
He's slumped because he's shot. Slumped don't mean dead.
那你也许认为神枪手和智多星也活着...
I guess you think that Butch and Sundance live too...
...你没看见他们死 只看见他们被团团包围
...even though you never see them dead, and they're surrounded.
这么说你是历史专家?
So you're some kind of history buft?
对 我常看历史和传记
Yeah, I generally read histories and biographies.
书上写的不可全信
Well' don't believe everything you read.
我没说我只看了一本书
Well' I didn't say I read just one book.
同一题材的书我尽量都看 弄清全部事实...
I try to read all the books on a subject. You know, try to get all the facts...
...然后自己判断究竟发生了什么
...and then decide for myself what really happened.
弄清全部事实 你很聪明
Mm-hm. Get all the facts. Yeah, that's smart.
你比法利强得多
You're much better at this than Farley.
在大家听烦了之前我们言归正传
Before we start to bore everyone, let's get back to business.
首先是我的要求
First, my list of demands.
一: 把我的警徽还给我
One: I want my badge brought down here.
二: 如果我死了 举行警方葬礼
Two: If I die, I want a departmental funeral.
这里没人会死
No one's gonna die here.
三: 找到那个告密人
Three: I want the informant found.
只有他能还我清白...
He's the one that can clear my name...
...他知道谁是这个阴谋的主使
...and he's the one who knows who's running this conspiracy.
四: 我要知道谁杀了我的搭档
Four: I wanna know who killed my partner.
8小时找不到告密人或凶手...
now, if neither the informant or killer is found in eight hours...
...我每小时杀1个人质 直到他们死光
...I Will kill one hostage an hour until they're all dead.
五:
Five:
我要和你当面谈 马上
I wanna talk to you face to face now.
- 现场指挥在楼上?  - 对 但你可以跟我说
- Commander's upstairs? - Yeah, but you can talk to me.
- 你是局长?  - 是的 我是特拉维斯
- You're the chief? - Yes. Travis.
很高兴见到你 你是贝克?
Nice to meet you. You're Beck?
- 你是...?  - 法利
- You're...? - Farley.
法利
Farley.
给我防弹衣
All right. Vest.
- 你要上去?  - 是的
- You're going up there? - Yes.
- 为什么不劝他下来?  - 他不会听
- Why didn't you talk him down? - He would have expected it.
他的资料
His sheet, please.
- 谁知道他为什么找我?  - 我们还想问你呢
- Know why he asked for me? - We Were hoping you could answer that.
我不知道 心理评估谁做的?
I can't. Psych evaluation? Who's on it?
- 是唐瑞  - 他认为自己是无辜的
- That's Tonray. - He may actually think he's innocent.
可能不得不动武 我们有个计划
We're probably gonna have to go tactical. We've put a plan together.
若能引开他的注意力 突击小组从这里进去
If we distract him long enough, we can send in an infiltration team.
- 先不忙采取行动 - 他妻子来了
- Let's wait on that. - The Wife's here.
天哪 他怎么样? 谁在跟他谈?
Oh' God. how is he? Has he hurt anyone? Who's talking to him?
凯伦 他没事 他要见克瑞斯・塞比安
Karen, he's okay. He asked for Chris Sabian.
- 克瑞斯・塞比安  - 我是克瑞斯・塞比安
- Chris Sabian. - I'm Chris Sabian.
- 你认识丹尼?  - 不认识
- Do you know Danny? - No.
他们说的那些全是无中生有 你要帮他
Doesn't matter to you, but he didn't do those things. You have to help him.
我不知道丹尼是否有罪 这不是我来的目的
I have no idea about Danny,s guilt or innocence.
我要带他安全地出来 你若想帮忙...
I'm here to get him out safely. So if you wanna help...
...去回答唐瑞几个问题 然后回家
...go with Tonray, ansWer his questions, and we'll drive you home.
不 我不回家
No. No, I'm not going home.
罗曼夫人...
Mrs. Roman...
...你只能增加这里的紧张与不安
...you bring tension and emotion to a scene that already has too much of both.
我绝不离开我丈夫
I am not leaving my husband.
你想帮他就先帮我
All right, fine, but if you wanna help him, help me.
我现在必须上去 他想跟我谈
I have to get up there. He wants to talk to me.
你回答唐瑞的问题 别走开 也许用得着你
Go with Tonray, answer his questions and then stay in case We need you.
- 我只能做到这种程度  - 凯伦 随我过来 谈一谈
- That's the best I can do. - Karen' come with me and talk, okay?
没事的
It's gonna be all right.
我怎么上去?
how do I get up?
乘电梯到18楼然后走楼梯
Take the freight elevator to 18. Walk the rest of the way.
我想掩护都准备好了
I assume you've got all these covered.
这是什么? 通向监察部的风道?
This is a shaft off Internal Affairs?
那是蒸气管 不能用
That's access to the steam pipes. It's unusable.
先把他的警徽拿来 再关掉暖气
All right. First' get his badge down there. Second, shut off the heat.
他会拿人质换暖气 几频道?
He might deal a hostage to get it back. What channel we on?
3频道 局长 你来看
Three. Chief, I wanna show you something.
- 丹尼 带我去  - 带他去吧
- Danny, take me. - Yeah. Yeah. Take him. Come on.
我有哮喘 知道吗?
I got the asthma. You know?
你不能让我去冒险
You can't put me in bad situations, man.
天哪 为什么总是看上我?
For chrissakes. Why you always pick on me?
我是什么人? 查理・布朗?
I mean, Who am I? Charlie Brown?
知道尼采怎么说:
You know what Nietzsche says:
即使最强壮的人 也有疲劳的时候
Even the strongest have their moments of fatigue.
我累了 丹尼
And I'm fatigued, Danny.
我实在太累了
I'm fucking fatigued.
- 你没事吧?  - 我像没事吗?
- You okay? - Do I look okay?
枪在背后指着我的头
I got a gun pointed at the back of my head.
你的裤子不错
Nice fucking pants.
住口 时装大师 过来
Shut up' Mr. Blackwell. Get over here.
- 在上班? - 差不多
- You Working? - Sort of.
在说服我妻子和女儿休战
I was negotiating a truce between my Wife and daughter.
相比之下比这里容易一点
That might prove to be easy by comparison.
不会让我感到惊讶
It wouldn't surprise me in the least.
- 你们关掉了暖气  - 你应该知道程序
- So you shut off the heat already. - You know how this works, Danny.
我知道
Yeah, I do.
下次你想骗人先把手机充足电
Next time you try and bluff, make sure you charge your cell phone.
告诉我 让我来干什么?
All right, now' you Wanna tell me what I'm doing up here?
我要当面告诉你我没有疯
I Wanted to tell you face to face I'm not crazy.
这样做只为证明我无辜
I'm just doing this to prove my innocence.
我相信你 我愿意尽力帮你出去...
I believe you. Anything I can do to help you get out...
别对我以恩人自居!
Don't fucking patronize me, man.
你不相信我是无辜的! 别说:
You don't think I'm innocent, so don't tell me:
"我愿意尽力帮你出去"
"I wanna do everything I can to help you get out."
别把我当成二流劫匪
Don't talk to me like I'm some second-rate HT.
你说的对 对不起 我错了
All right, you're right. I'm sorry. My mistake.
你没诚意 出去 锁上门
Yeah, you are sorry. Get out of here. Lock the door.
- 想谈再来电话  - 丹尼 我真的想谈
- Call when you wanna talk. - Danny, I'm ready to talk.
你说的对 你说的对
You're right. You're right.
我不知道你是否有罪
I don't know if you're innocent or not.
他们对你的指责可能是事实
You could've done everything they say.
那警察可能是你杀的 我不知道也管不着
You could have killed that cop. I don't know and I don't care.
有办法能证明你无辜 但这肯定不是
There are ways to prove your innocence. This is hardly one of them.
你扣押了人质...
And now you got hostages...
...我要告诉你:
...so let me tell you this:
你要是伤害他们 我将不再有兴趣跟你谈判
You hurt one of them, you burn up whatever currency you got to deal With me.
我只关心他们 不在乎你能否活着出去
They're all I care about. You leaving here walking is a distant second.
- 我说的够清楚吗?  - 很好
- now, do I make myself clear? - Good.
我们有进展了
now We're getting somewhere.
很好 回答我的问题 为什么叫我上来?
Good, now ansWer my question. What am doing I up here?
内森遇害前告诉我 偷钱的人是...
Before Nate Was killed, he told me the men involved in the fraud...
...我们分局的 我认识的人
...are from my precinct. Guys I know.
- 我称为朋友的人  - 那怎么样?
- Guys I might call friends. - And?
你不是
And you're not.
当朋友出卖你时...
When your friends betray you...
...唯一能信任的是陌生人
...sometimes the only people you can trust are strangers.
锁上门! 出去!
Lock the door! Get out! Get out!
快关门 锁上! 快点!
Come on! Hurry up. Lock it! Hurry up! Come on!
把手举起来!
Hold it right there.
贝克 怎么回事? 他回去了!
Beck. Beck, what happened? I've lost him! He's gone back in!
快走 快走
Come on! Go, go, go!
起来 起来!
Get up! Get up!
把枪扔掉! 扔掉!
Drop the guns! Drop them!
把枪丢掉!
Put it down!
你们在危害人质的生命!
You are jeopardizing the life of this hostage!
- 把枪丢掉!  - 把武器丢掉!
- Drop your gun! - Drop your weapon!
狙击小组 看见罗曼了?
Sniper team, can anyone see Roman?
找机会干掉他
Look for the one-shot.
已看见目标
We have the target acquired.
- 放开他  - 快放下枪!
- Put it down! - Drop the weapon!
- 放下枪! - 放下枪 丹尼!
- Drop your weapon now! - Drop it now, Danny!
放下枪
Drop the gun! Drop it!
放下武器!
Put it down! now!
放下武器! 丹尼
Put it down, Danny.
- 放下武器!  - 你们会让这个人送命!
- Drop it! - You're gonna get this man killed!
放下武器!
Drop your weapon!
放下枪
Put your gun down!
命令他 弗罗斯!
Tell him! Tell him, Frost!
快把枪放下!
Put the gun down now!
丢掉你的枪!
Drop your weapon!
绿灯 消灭目标
Green light. Take the subject out.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
巴勒莫 消灭目标
Palermo, take the subject out.
巴勒莫 消灭目标!
Palermo, take the subject out!
- 明白 - 别跟我说"明白"!
- Copy. - Don't tell me fucking "copy"!
- 快开枪!  - 明白!
- Pull the fucking trigger! - Copy.
我不能开枪
I cannot take the shot.
命令你开枪
Pull the fucking trigger.
- 不行 长官! 我不能开枪 - 下不了手!
- Negative, sir' I cannot take this shot. - Have a heart!
见鬼!
Fuck!
巴勒莫 退下 解除你的任务
Palermo, bring it in. You're relieved.
踢过来!
Kick it!
- 看来他的演讲奏效了  - 走开
- Looks like the HT's speech worked. - Stand back.
我们能行
We have this.
你是指挥还是他是指挥?
Is this your command or is it his?
你分散了他的注意力 我们找到机会了结此事
You had him distracted. We saw an opportunity to end this.
- 我们必须把握机会  - 你让我和人质的生命受到危胁
- We had to take it. - You put me and those hostages at risk.
那是你的方式 不是我的方式! 应先谈判!
That's what you did, and that's not how I work. First' we talk.
是我的命令
It was my call.
我们觉得此人不可能被说服
We don't feel this man can be talked down.
是吗? 我来了才半个小时 你怎么知道?
Oh' really? I've been here a half-hour! how do you know that?
怒我直言...
With all due respect, sir...
...我保持着5年谈判零伤亡的纪录...
...I have kept a zero casualty rate for five years...
...因为这种行动是最后手段!
...because this kind of action is a last resort.
这里不归你指挥 塞比安
This is not your command, Sabian.
没错 可是我有责任 那就是救那些人出来
Yeah, that's right. My command is to get those people out safely.
- 那是我的责任! - 你不了解这个人 中尉!
- That's my command! - You don't know this man, lieutenant!
他操纵了整个局势 巴勒莫就受了他的影响
He's manipulating this situation. Look what he did to Palermo.
他会将所有人各个击破...
He's gonna fuck With every single fucking one of you...
...如果给他足够时间 他知道你能办到
...if we give him enough time, and he knows you'll do it.
- 他熟悉你的工作  - 他说的有道理 塞比安
- He knows how you fucking Work. - He's got a point, Sabian.
我们有我们的指挥系统
We do have a chain of command.
你的指挥系统多给了他两名人质
Your chain of command has just given Danny two more hostages.
他若杀掉其中一个 你负责吗? 反正我不负责!
Officers. You gonna take responsibility if he takes one of them out? Because I don't!
他们等着接手 你想这样?
They're just waiting to take this over. You want that to happen?
你可以做个简单决定
This is gonna be very easy for you.
罗曼要我来 我会跟他谈
Roman asked for me and he's gonna get me.
要么按我的方法 要么我走
We're gonna do it my way or I walk.
我很乐意马上离开 把责任留给你
I got no truck with leaving you with this responsibility.
现在由你选择 或让他们接管这里的一切
now, it's your decision, or they're gonna fucking take it over.
现在由你指挥
You have command for now.
但我仍是现场最高官衔...
But I'm still the ranking officer on the scene...
...我有监督权
...and I will be watching.
好 你监督 帮个忙
Good. You watch. now do me a favor.
劳驾把我介绍给我的队员
Please introduce me to our team.
都听着...
Attention...
...我是艾尔・特拉维斯局长
...this is your chief, Al Travis.
向你介绍谈判专家克瑞斯・塞比安...
I would like to introduce you to the negotiator' Chris Sabian...
...从现在起 他负责全权指挥
...who' as of now, has full command.
我是克瑞斯・塞比安 即刻起有决定要经我批准
My name is Chris Sabian, and as of right now' all decisions go through me.
不是我下的命令一概无效
No order is valid unless I give it.
未经我批准不得采取任何行动
No action is taken unless prior approved by me.
相信我们能很好配合 共同努力...
I know we understand each other and that we'II work together...
...安全 迅速解决此事
...to try to end this safely and quickly.
没有打中 贝克! 我还活着!
It didn't Work, Beck! I'm still alive, motherfucker!
丹尼 我是克瑞斯
Danny, it's Chris.
丹尼 拿起对讲机回答我
Danny, Danny, listen to me. Pick up the radio and talk to me' man.
我没事! 看!
Nothing! Look!
拿摄像机的都拍下来了?
You guys with the cameras, you get that?
我只要求多一点时间 他们就想杀死我!
All I asked for Was more time' and they tried to take me out!
这就是芝加哥警方解决人质危急的原则...
It is the policy of the Chicago police to resolve all hostage situations...
...最大限度保护人的生命!
...with the utmost regard for the preservation of life!
去叫他妻子 我们可能需要她
Get his Wife. We might need her.
你们杀我吗? 那就杀吧!
You want my blood? Take my blood! Come on!
我在这里! 开枪吧!
Here it is! Take it!
他们瞄准了 马上可以结束!
Chief, they have a shot. We can end it here.
不许开枪 你想在电视前打死他?
No one takes that shot. You wanna shoot him on television?
让人群后退 远离大楼
Move the crowd. I want the area clear.
动手打死我吧!
Go ahead' take my blood!
开枪吧!
Go ahead' take the shot!
丹尼!
Danny!
我离真相只有一步之遥 所以他们要杀掉我...
I'm getting too close to the truth and they wanna kill me...
...像杀掉内森那样!
...just like they killed Nate!
局长 下令开枪 他妈的快下令开枪!
Chief, give me the order. Give the fucking order!
- 等等  - 不准开枪!
- Wait. - Do not take the shot!
我要怎么做他们才肯听我说?
What am I gonna have to do to be heard, huh?
非要逼我伤人才能得到尊重?
Am I gonna have to hurt somebody to get respect?
好吧 我会的!
Well' all right! All right, I will!
你不想这么做 不想让事情进一步恶化
Danny, listen to me. Don't do that. Don't take this to the next level.
你能听见吗?
Can he fucking hear me?
他有没有对讲机?
Does he have a radio?
以为你能杀人后逍遥法外
Think you can come in here and just shoot me' huh?
他们派你来杀我? 以为能杀了我就转身跑掉?
They send you to kill me and you just do it? You just think you can get away With it?
我知道你是他们一伙的
I know you're one of them. I know you are.
你要为你对我做的事付出代价!
now you're gonna fucking pay for doing that!
丹尼 不要伤害任何人 不要这么做
Danny. Danny, do not hurt anyone. Do not do that, all right?
现在这里由我负责
I am in command here.
没有人会突击 没人会闯入
No one is gonna breach. No one is gonna come in.
没人敢不听我的命令行事 我全权负责
No one is gonna do anything without my authority. I'm in control here.
你不是负责人! 他们才是! 他们不听你的 克里斯
You are not in control! They are! They're not listening to you' Chris.
我要给他们点颜色看看!
So l'm gonna show them why they should!
你派来的每一个王八蛋都得送命!
One of the son-of-a-bitches you sent in is about to die!
来一个 我杀一个!
And every time you try to come in, this will happen!
走 走!
now move! Move!
进去 进去!
Get in there. Get in there!
蹲下 蹲下!
down! down!
你是他们一伙的 斯科特? 陷害我的那群人之一?
Are you one of them, Scott? One of the men that set me up?
所以你想我翘辫子?
Is that why you want me dead?
是我 凯伦
It's me, Karen.
丹尼 和我说话
Danny, please talk to me.
天啊
Oh' my God.
别再派人来了
Do not come in here again.
凯伦 对不起
Karen, I'm sorry.
切断电源 马上切断
Cut the electric. Cut it now.
几个小时按兵不动之后 刚才市政大楼20层...
After hours of little action, we've witnessed a flurry of activity...
...发生短暂暴乱
...on the 20th floor of the Chicago administration building.
看来下面还有更多行动
And it looks like there's a little more action going on now.
他们移开路障
They'Ne cleared the barricades.
几辆看似普通的车... 其实是警车...
Looks like plainclothes... Actually, those are federal sedans...
...载着联邦特工抵达现场
...FBI agents, in fact, arriving on the scene.
这是本次事件的一个很大进展 因为到目前为止...
This is a major development for this story, because up until now...
...谈判一直由芝加哥警方单独进行
...this negotiation has been handled by the Chicago police department.
联邦调查局可能是来协助谈判...
With the arrival of the feds, they are either coming to aid in the negotiation...
...也可能是来接管谈判
...or perhaps, more likely, to take over the negotiations.
不过这只是猜想 只知道他们到达现场 ...
But that is all speculation. All we know is that they are now on the scene...
...我们等待并关注...
...and we'll have to wait and see...
你干了什么 丹尼?
What have you done' Danny?
你把自己彻底毁了 你杀了警察
Danny, you just fucked yourself completely. You killed a cop!
你杀了一个无辜的人!
You killed an innocent man!
他不是无辜的
He wasn't innocent.
是他们一伙的 他要杀我
He's one of them. He tried to kill me.
进来时我说过 不搞清真相我不走
I told you all when I came in here I wasn't leaving till I got the truth.
无论需要在这里待多久
I don't care how long it takes.
你本可以避免这些
You could've prevented this.
你干嘛不告诉他?
Why don't you just tell him something' Niebaum?
你就对他说点什么吧
Why don't you just fucking tell him anything?
督察?
Inspector?
5年了 麦琪
Five years, Maggie.
你不会一无所知
You must know something.
- 说吧 督察  - 麦琪
- Please, inspector. - Maggie.
他明知有人会送命 仍坚持撒谎
He already lied when he knew it would cost someone their life.
你若知道什么 快告诉我
now, if you know something, anything, you tell me now.
他将所有私人资料存在电脑里
He keeps all his personal files on the computer.
我不该知道这些 可我知道
I'm not supposed to know about them, but I do.
里面很多东西 可能对你有帮助
There's a lot of stuff on there. Probably could help you.
弗罗斯
Frost.
打开手铐 去搬电脑
Unlock yourself. Get the computer.
我看见你们的人到了
I just saw your troops moving in.
我不能让你们接手...
I don't want a situation where you and the ATF take over the situation...
...在没有证据的情况下 再次把事情弄得不可收拾
...without any fucking evidence whatsoever. I don't want you going in.
不许派人进去 这事上各大报纸前我只有1小时
I want a guarantee before the press starts that I have an hour.
- 来电话了 - 我知道
- Phone's ringing. - I know.
- 再给我1小时 你们保证  - 你接不接电话?
- Another hour. I want a guarantee. - You gonna answer the phone?
- 谢谢  - 最后一次
- Yes. Thank you. - You have one shot.
你究竟接还是不接?
Are you gonna get that or what?
- 喂  - 抱歉打扰 这么久才接电话?
- Yes. - Sorry to interrupt. What took you so long?
- 我很忙  - 忙?
- I'm busy. - Busy?
给你个忠告 别让挟持人久等
A piece of advice: Never keep a hostage-taker waiting. It pisses him off.
放心 他会再打
Relax. He'll call back.
你以为你在对谁...?
Who the fuck you think you're dealing with...?
你若有困难 可以让我们处理
If you have a problem, lieutenant, maybe you wanna let us handle this.
告诉他我这就上去
Tell him I'm on my way up. Please, tell him.
- 法利 接电话  - 好的
- Farley, get the phone. - Yeah.
- 塞比安 - 不 我是法利...
- Sabian... - No, it's Far...
克瑞斯上去了
Danny, Chris is on his way up.
我们需要重新开始谈判
We need to reopen negotiations.
- 什么? 你有求于我?  - 我要求给我恢复供电
- I'm sorry. You want something from me? - I want the electricity turned back on.
你在向我...
You want something...
...寻求帮助?
...from me?
你以为杀人能增加谈判筹码?
You think killing a man gives you the poWer to negotiate?
为什么? 丹尼・罗曼 你以为你了解我?
Why is that, Danny Roman? Because you think you know me?
以为你能信任我?
Because you think you can trust me?
以为你知道我会怎么做? 我会为你争取时间?
You think you know what I'm gonna do' that I'm gonna give you time?
别指望这能帮你
Don't you fucking count on it.
现在只有我一人...
Right now, I'm the only thing between you...
...站在你和一支急于冲进来杀你的部队之间
...and an army that's just itching to walk in here and take you out.
丹尼 你说我干嘛要挡他们的道?
So you tell me something, Danny. Why should I get in their way, huh?
你说我干嘛要...
Make me believe why I should deal with you...
...再跟你谈判
...ever again.
我手上还有人质
I still have hostages.
他们还会为你的错误受到惩罚
They can still be punished for your mistakes.
你在威胁我? 你刚刚在威胁我?
What was that, a threat? Did you just threaten me?
我正巴不得一走了之
That's all I need to walk out.
谈判规则上说...
The rules of engagement state...
...挟持者扬言杀人报复 不可冒险进攻
...you don't risk a breach if the hostage-taker is willing to kill in retaliation.
我已证明我会这么做
And I think I've proved I'm willing to do that.
有些现象不代表事实 克瑞斯
Things are not What they seem, Chris.
你看见他的行为了
You saw What they did.
他们瞒着你进攻 因为他们要我死
They didn't tell you they were coming in' because they Want me dead.
你再开枪...
One more gun goes off...
...我就亲自下令进攻 明白吗?
...and I'm gonna give the order to move in myself. You understand?
别以为你请我来 就能得到我的同情
Don't think you've bought anything by asking me to come here.
因为你要记住 我是一个陌生人
Because you need to remember I am a stranger to you.
你不知道我能做些什么
You have no idea what I'm capable of.
我需要电...
I need the electricity...
...打开电脑查看尼鲍姆的资料
...so I can turn on that computer and get a look at Niebaum's files.
还要食品和毯子给人质
I also Want food and blankets for the hostages.
我要一名人质交换 不然一切免谈
I'll need a hostage. Nothing less.
带弗罗斯走
Take Frost.
- 马上恢复供电  - 请重复一遍
- Turn the electricity back on. - Could you repeat that, Sabian?
我带一名人质出来 照我的话做
I'm about to walk out with a hostage. Do what I say.
恢复供电
Turn the electricity back on.
信用卡诈骗 电子盗窃 你为这个被捕的 鲁迪?
Credit-card fraud and electronic theft. That's you, right, Rudy?
被捕是这两项罪名: 信用卡诈骗 和偷电...
Well' I got caught for credit-card fraud and electronic theft...
...其实远不止这些
...but the list goes on, you know. Heh.
我可能坐到天亮一无所获
Look, I could sit here all night and get nothing.
你们用什么程序加密?
You know? What kind of security has this thing got?
F1 回车
F1 ' enter.
(使用者姓名: )
C...
...-I-COM.
...dash I dash COM.
G-9.
(搜寻中)
运行查找
Run a search.
查找所有和伤残基金有关的资料
Look for anything that has to do with the disability fund.
(查找伤残基金)
这里还设了很多密码
There's a lot of added security here.
还不错 我只落后了6个月
It's not bad. It's just outdated by six months.
该死的警察 总是慢两步
Mm. Fucking cops. Always two steps behind.
他在寻求人们相信他
He's looking for people to believe in him.
我没帮上什么忙
I don't think I helped the situation.
他就杀了斯科特
Then he shoots Scott.
天哪 我无能为力
Christ. I couldn't do anything.
弗罗斯
Frost.
告诉我丹尼和伤残基金的关系...
It would be helpful if you could tell me...
...他的案子和那个告密人 这样会帮了我一个大忙
...about Danny,s relationship to the fund, his case and specifically, this informant.
你听到或知道的任何有关情况...
Anything you might have overheard or know...
...你觉得可能对我有用的细节
...that might be of use to me, that you think is pertinent.
当然
Sure.
"伤残基金
"Disability fund.
子目录: 监听和录音带"
Subdirectories: Wires and taps."
- 点击"监听"  - 好的
- Click on wires. - Okay.
被偷听的人真多
Oh' man, there's a lot of wires.
- 这些号码是什么? - 警徽编号
- What are these numbers? - Cops' badge numbers.
往下走
Okay, now scroll down.
停 往上走一个
Stop, stop' stop. Back up one.
这是内森的警徽
That's Nate's badge. Okay.
点击
Click that.
他们查过帐...
Well, they did do an audit...
...可什么也没发现
...but they didn't prove anything.
嘿 那是我的声...
Hey, that's my voice...
若有人偷我们的钱 我们必须找出是谁
Somebody's taking our money. We gotta find out who it is.
见鬼!
Oh, shit!
你这混蛋
You son of a bitch.
给内森安了窃听器
You were tapping Nate.
你早知道他在调查基金
You knew he was investigating the fraud.
- 你撒谎! - 见你的鬼!
- You lied. - Fuck you!
你杀了他 因为他就要查出真相
And then you killed him because he was getting too close.
我们监听很多警员 可这屋里只有一个凶手
Tap a lot of cops. There's only one killer in this room.
我不是凶手 你才是凶手
I'm not the killer here, you are.
返回到10月12日 内森被害的前一晚
Scroll back to October 12th, the night before Nate was killed.
- 只有一个录音 - 打开!
- There's only one recording. - Click on it!
好的 好的
All right, all right.
告诉我出了什么事?
Are you gonna talk to me?
我正在查一个案子...
It's that case I'm working on. It's, uh...
我去去就来 对不起 我很快回来
Look, l'II just be a minute. Sorry, honey. I won't be long.
我只想看看他在不在
I just wanna see if he's here, you know?
我不能在电话上跟他谈...
I don't wanna talk to him on the phone. It's just not...
我马上就过来 你等我一会
I'll see you soon, okay? I'll just be a minute.
- 好吗  - 好的?
- Okay. - Okay?
- 我爱你  - 我也爱你
- I love you. - Mm-hm. I love you too.
他是去见那个告密人?
He was going to see his informant, wasn't he?
你不知道自己在说什么
Ha-ha-ha. You don't know what you're talking about.
内森遇害前一天晚上对我说 他刚见过告密人
The night before Nate was killed he told me he had just talked to his informant.
是的
Yeah, yeah.
这你也知道
You knew that too.
出了什么事 尼鲍姆?
What's going on here, Niebaum?
你为什么找不到这个人?
Why can't you find this guy, huh?
你一定找过他 想把他杀掉!
You gotta be looking for him so you can shut him up too!
你不知道他是谁 对吗?
You don't know who he is, do you?
琳达不告诉你那晚他们去了哪里
Linda wouldn't tell you where they went that night, would she?
她认为你和我同样有罪!
Because she thinks you're as guilty as I am.
- 说吧 丹尼  - 这是私人线路吗?
- Go ahead. - Is this a private line?
- 你想单独谈?  - 是的
- You need it to be? - Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
说吧
Go ahead.
我要你找内森的妻子琳达谈谈
I need you to talk to Linda Roenick, Nate's wife.
谈什么?
About what?
我找到录音证明 尼鲍姆一直在撒谎
I found some taps that prove Niebaum's been lying all along.
我听到些情况需要你问琳达
I heard something on one of them. I need you to ask Linda about it.
你一个人去
You and only you.
要我问她什么?
What do you want me to ask her?
10月12日晚 内森死的前一天
Ask her where she and Nate went on October 12th, the night before he died.
她们去找谁?
Who he talked to.
她说出内森见了谁 我再给你一个人质
If she tells you who he saw, I'll give you another hostage.
她什么都不说 你什么也没有
If she tells you nothing, you get nothing.
准备好人质
Have my hostage ready.
太好了
Great. All right.
- 请原谅  - 我得走了
- Excuse me. - I gotta go.
- 能谈谈吗?  - 谈吧
- Can we have a word? - Yes.
赫尔曼研究了大楼设计图 他们有个建议
Hellman's been studying the blueprints with Beck. They have a suggestion.
你肯听建议?
You do take suggestions?
他认为可派人从通风管靠近罗曼
Hellman thinks we can get a team in the vent system right above Roman.
我们建议派人进去 以应付紧急情况 就一个小组
What we're suggesting is getting men in place for a crisis entry. Just one unit.
以防万一
Only as a precaution.
这样能将他制服 如果他杀害人质
With this type of entry, we can control him in case he starts shooting hostages.
扔颗闪光弹 二三秒就能控制局面
We can go in there strong, two, three seconds from bang to bullets.
我们不是要全面进攻
Sabian, we're not asking for a full breach.
只是担心他杀害另一个兄弟
We have a real concern he may kill one of our men.
你可能无所谓 可对我们很重要
That may not mean much to you, but it means a hell of a lot to us.
贝克 别这样
Beck, please.
克瑞斯 我们想有备无患
Chris, I just wanna be ready to go if we need to.
我同意指挥官的看法 也担心我的队员受伤
I agree with the commander's assessment, and I do care if our team is injured...
...可无论丹尼做什么 不经我批准...
...but they don't move an inch, no mater What Danny does...
...他们不得前进1英寸
...without my authorization.
- 先生们?  - 没问题
- Gentlemen? - Without a doubt.
赛比安
Sabian.
我们制造机会 你趁机干掉他
Allen' we're gonna make an opportunity. We'll take him out if we get the shot.
明白
Right.
这里怎么样?
how you holding up?
很好
Good.
你下去休息一会
Why don't you take a little break?
我带你们进去 该结束了
I'm gonna get us inside. We're gonna end this thing.
动手吧
Let's do it.
- 有人要去洗手间吗?  - 我要去
- Anybody gotta use the bathroom? - Yes, I do.
还有我
Me too.
厕所在哪里 麦琪?
Where is it, Maggie?
街对面意大利小饭馆里有一个...
There's one across the street in a nice restaurant...
...但可能去不成
...but I'm sure that's probably out of the question.
你可以去 只要能忍到我们出去
You can use that one if you can hold it till we get out of here.
走廊那头有一个
There's one down the hall.
谢谢
Thank you.
她走后你用这个
When she's gone, use this.
我们要控制大厦 占领19层...
You bet' we need to contain the building. I need teams on 19...
...20层 21层
...20 and 21.
- 是 长官 - 封锁大厅
- Yes, sir. - And secure the lobby.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
- 塞比安在外面干什么? - 不知道
- What the hell is Sabian doing up there? - No idea.
1小时前来了个男人 他们一直在谈
Guy came in about an hour ago. They've been talking ever since.
这么久还没有答复?
Why the hell is this taking so long?
他们想拖垮丹尼 让他疲惫不堪
They're trying to wear down Danny so he gets tired.
你为何列出这些警察和他们的银行帐户 尼鲍姆?
Why the hell do you have all these cops and their accounts in here, Niebaum?
为何调查你也参与的诈骗案?
Why are you investigating a fraud that you're part of?
我没有参与诈骗
I'm not part of any fraud.
是不是发现了他们揩基金的油 你就勒索他们?
Did you out find these cops Were skimming from the fund and you blackmailed them?
你负责这部份?
Is that how it works?
为何挑他们? 这些人拿不到大钱
Why these cops? These guys don't have access to the money.
这主要是保险欺诈 对吗?
Well' it's basically insurance fraud, right?
- 什么?  - 是...
- What? - It's...
有些人...
Somebody...
名单上的人申请虚假赔偿
Some of these guys on this list submit false claims.
和我做过的汽车保险一样... 我认识的一个人...
It's like this auto-body thing I pulled... I mean, some guy I know...
他对保险公司说他的车撞毁了 对吗?
He would tell the insurance company his car had been wrecked, right?
- 很简单  - 然后呢?
- It's very simple. - And then?
若没保险经纪人的份 他休想拿到赔偿
Well' he'd never get paid if the claims agent Wasn't in on it.
需要有人处理文件 并为你掩盖?
So you need somebody with access to put the paperWork through, then cover it up.
对了
Bingo.
你干的就是这部份
That's where you come in.
对吗? 罗曼
Isn't it, Roman?
怎么回事 赛比安? 这人是谁?
All right, what is this, Sabian? Who is this?
你马上会知道
You're about to find out.
- 丹尼? - 和琳达谈了?
- Danny? - You talk to Linda?
我干的更漂亮 我找到了你的告密人
I've done one better. I found your informant.
你要把所有人质交给我
You're gonna end up giving me all my hostages.
凯尔・温格罗警长
Sergeant Cale Wangro.
他知道哪些人参与
He knows who's involved.
内森死后他不敢出面...
He was afraid to come forward after Nathan was killed...
...他不能肯定你和他们是不是一伙
...and he Wasn't sure whether you were involved.
都有谁?
Well' who was it?
听着 丹尼 这件事牵连很多人
Listen' Danny. This is gonna implicate too many people.
联邦调查局的人在这里 他们将为他录口供以确保公平
So the FBI is here. They're ready to take his statement to ensure impartiality.
不能在电话上透露 问题解决了
But I cannot have this go over the air, all right, so it's over, Danny.
结束了 出来吧
It's done. Come on out.
- 让我妻子过去  - 叫他妻子
- Get my wife in there. - Get his wife.
- 他们找到告密人 - 谢天谢地
- They found the informant. - Oh, thank God!
谢天谢地
Yes! Thank God!
祝贺你 麦琪 你可以走了
Congratulations' Maggie. You are free to go.
督察先生 去你的 谢谢 谢谢
Inspector, fuck you very much. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
"让我的子民离去" 来 放开我
Let my people go, man! Come on, man. Give it up.
克瑞斯 等一下
Chris, hold on a second.
是警校同学 我们一起在6分区工作过
We were at the academy. We worked at Area 6 together.
克瑞斯 让告密人接电话
Chris, put Nate's informant on.
丹尼 我不想广播出去
Danny, I don't want this broadcast.
他若能还我清白 我想跟他谈谈
Look, if he can clear my name, I wanna talk to him' now.
丹尼 我是凯尔
Danny, this is Cale.
凯尔 你很勇敢能站出来
Hi, Cale. Very brave of you to come down like this.
我有很多问题
You know I have a lot of questions.
首先 都有谁参与了...
Let's just start with, uh, who was involved...
...这阴谋? 凯尔
...in this conspiracy, for 500, Cale.
我不能当众点出他们的名字
I can't name names, not in front of everyone here.
- 这样做不恰当  - 别跟我说什么恰当
- Wouldn't be, uh, appropriate. - I don't wanna hear about appropriate.
告诉我哪些人参与了 都有谁?
Just tell me who Was involved. now, who was it?
你认识的人
Men you know, Danny.
还有其他人...
There may be others...
...我只知道几个关键人名
...but I only know the names of the key players.
别逼我指名道姓
Don't make me say their names.
(当警察多少年了? )
你为什么不找尼鲍姆?
Why didn't you go see Niebaum?
我不知道尼鲍姆是否被收买保持沉默
I didn't know if Niebaum was getting paid off to be quiet or not.
我不相信他或监察部
I couldn't trust him or Internal Affairs.
- 有人提过他的名字  - 所以尼鲍姆肯定参与了
- I did hear his name mentioned. - So Niebaum was definitely involved.
谢谢
Thanks, Cale.
你怎么认识内森的?
now, how did you know Nate?
警校同学
From the academy.
你当警察多久了?
how long you been on the job?
- 从74年起 怎么了?  - 最后一次见到内森是何时?
- Since '74. Why? - When's the last time you met with Nate?
他死的前一天晚上
The night before he died.
很好
Good.
我们有进展了
now We're getting somewhere.
丹尼
Dan.
(告密人)
等一下 凯尔
Hold on, Cale.
(勒尼克 内森 内务监察部)
(教育：亚历桑那州立大学)
对不起...
Sorry' um...
内森跟我说 你们在科罗拉多大学打过棒球 是吗?
So Nate tells me, uh, you played ball with him at Colorado State, that right?
对 可这与此事有何关系?
Yeah, but what's this have to do with anything?
他上的是亚利桑那大学
Well' he went to Arizona State, Cale.
叫克瑞斯接电话
Put Chris on the phone.
赛比安 你勇气可佳 但你的把戏不管用
Nice try, Sabian. Your little bluff didn't work.
尼鲍姆说内森是他的告密人 他为监察部工作
Niebaum told me Nate was his informant. See' he worked for IAD.
一直替尼鲍姆工作 他说的知情人是他自己
Worked for Niebaum all along. He was describing himself.
只是不想让我知道
Just didn't Want me to know.
尼鲍姆说他没参与谋杀
now, Niebaum says he was not part of the murder.
怎么回事 赛比安?
What's going on here, Sabian?
- 他用我们的方法对付尼鲍姆  - 不过他答应出庭作证
- He's using our bluft against Niebaum. - He's willing to testify.
如果你们同意免诉他谋杀罪 他会说出名字
He'll name names if you grant him immunity on the murder charge.
再回电话谈条件
You call me back if we have a deal.
丹尼...
Danny, talk...
被他看破了
We've been made.
你干什么? 我没说我没同意?
What are you doing? I didn't make a deal. What the fuck are you doing?
可他们以为你说了 尼鲍姆
They think you did, Niebaum.
你不是说没有阴谋吗? 所以不用担心
But there is no "they," right? So you don't shit have to worry about.
那是你的计谋?
This was a bluft?
- 要看你处在哪个位置?  - 你知道这事? 弗罗斯
- That all depends on your position. - Did you know about this, Frost?
不 我不知道
No. No, I didn't.
我告诉他 我知道内森有个告密人
I told him What I knew about Nathan's informant.
你就这样利用我的信息?
This is how you use that information?
让我们相信他是无辜的...
Making us think he's innocent after all those...
你以为你是谁?
Who the fuck do you think you are?
我可以任意使用信息以结束这个局面
I can use information any way I want to try to end this.
我不知道谁是无辜的 我正在设法查清楚
I don't know who's innocent. That's what I'm trying to find out.
别再叫我来参加你们的猜谜游戏
Don't call me in here to be part of your charades again.
凯伦 你...
Karen, you...
给他打电话
Get him back.
凯伦
Karen.
凯伦 现在我不知道该相信谁
Karen, right now' understand I don't know who to trust.
上面的还是里面的
Up there or in there.
这计谋不只是针对丹尼
The bluff wasn't just for Danny.
走开 鲁迪
Move, Rudy.
走开!
Move!
谁杀了内森?
Who killed Nate?
尼鲍姆 他们能杀内森 难道不会杀你?
They killed Nate, Niebaum. Think they won't kill you?
该死的!
Fuck it.
你要干什么?
Fuck are you doing?
你要推我去哪里? 不
Where are you taking me? No!
我什么也不知道!
I know nothing!
因为你陷害我 他们要杀我!
They're gonna take me out because you set me up!
你要害死另一个无辜的人! 我什么也不知道!
You'll get another innocent man killed! I know nothing!
别把我扔在屋里!
Don't put me in that fucking room!
好的 好的!
Okay, okay!
别让我进去!
Don't put me in that room!
内森 拿录音带来找我
Nate. Nate came to me With taps.
我找到了录音带上的那些人
I went to the guys who were implicated in the taps.
他们收买我毁掉证据 我同意了
They offered me money to lose the evidence. I did it.
知道了? 是一次性交易!
Okay? It was a one-time deal!
他们收买内森 他拒绝了 他们就杀了他
They offered the same thing to Nate. They killed him.
- 录音带上有谁?  - 让我离开门口...
- Who's on the taps? - Get me out of this fucking...
- 录音带上有谁? - 你所有朋友!
- Who's on the fucking taps? - All your friends!
谁?
Who?
阿尔金托...
Argento...
...赫尔曼 埃伦
...Hellman, Allen. Yeah.
- 你胡说! - 不
- That's bullshit! - No.
我有证据 录音带上的对话...
I have proof! I have them on taps...
...讨论怎样从基金里偷钱
...talking about how they took money out of the fund.
他们自己办不到 谁是主谋?
They couldn't do that themselves. Who's in charge?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 那录音在这电脑里?  - 不
- Are those taps on this computer? - No.
在哪里?
Where are they?
我放在安全的地方!
I have them somewhere safe!
空中突击1号 有民用直升机靠近 快躲开
Air Tac 1, civilian unit approaching. Peel away.
你飞进联邦政府控制的现场上空
Yeu are flying in a government crime-scene airspace.
你必须遵守警戒法保持2英里的规定
It is imperative you respect the two-mile boundary law.
请立即离开大楼
Turn away from the building.
重复 请立即离开大楼
I repeat, turn away from the building.
- 谁开枪? - 趴下! 趴下! 大家趴下!
- Who's firing? - down! down! Everyone down!
是谁开的枪?
Who the hell just fired?
- 开始进攻 - 不! 不要进攻!
- Initiate breach. - No, no, no! Do not breach!
让我过去! 让我过去!
Let me through! Let me through!
队员安全受到威胁 第1小组报告情况
Team's position has been compromised. Unit 1, status?
- 派第1小组进入  - 熄灭照明 第1小组
- Send in Unit 1. - Kill the lights, Unit 1.
第1小组报告情况
Unit 1, give me status.
第1小组已进入
Unit 1, we're coming in.
该死!
Hell Fuck!
冲!
Move!
他有闪光弹!
He's got flashbangs!
冲! 冲!
Move! Move!
该死!
Hell Fuck!
撤! 撤!
Get down!
消灭他!
Take him out.
消灭目标!
Take the subject out.
别开枪!
Do not fire!
我没有下命令! 不许开枪!
Do not! I did not give the order! Do not!
停止进攻!
Terminate this breach.
丹尼 听见了吗?
Danny, can you hear me?
麦琪 你没事吧?
Maggie, you okay?
鲁迪? 马科斯?
Rudy? Markus?
糟了! 糟了!
Oh' shit. Shit!
他被打中了
They shot him.
坚持住 督察 坚持住
Hold on, inspector. Just hold on.
我马上叫人来救你
I'll get somebody up here to help you.
挺住
Come on.
丹尼 听见了吗?
Danny, can you hear me?
上面还有人受伤吗?
Danny, is anyone else hurt up there?
坚持住 别死
Come on, come on. down.
丹尼 上面有人受伤吗?
Danny, is anyone hurt up there?
坚持住
Come on. Hold on.
我叫人上来
I'm gonna get somebody. Come on.
快派人上来! 尼鲍姆受...
Get somebody up here! Niebaum's been...
天哪
Oh' God.
他死了!
He's dead!
听见了吗 克瑞斯? 他们杀了他
You hear that, Chris? They killed him.
天啊
Holy Jesus.
丹尼 你伤了吗?
Danny, are you shot?
丹尼 上面还有人受伤吗?
Danny, is anyone hurt up there?
还有人受伤吗?
Anyone else hurt up there?
怎么回事? 我刚离开就死人?
What the hell happened? I step out of this room and someone gets killed?
那是意外 你让我的人怎么办?
It was an accident. What did you expect my men to do?
擅自开枪 是谁先开的枪?
A gun went off. Any idea Who shot first?
我们有什么可指责的? 我的人是应付突发事件!
What the fuck are you accusing us of? My men responded to a situation!
爆竹响 你们也采取同样行动?
If a firecracker goes off, you respond the same way?
我们又不了解情况 我们是怎么说的?
We don't know what happened. What did we agree to?
无论丹尼做什么 没有我的命令谁也不能进去
That no matter what, no one goes in without my authority.
我们说好的!
That's what we agreed on.
你们看不见 也听不见上面的情况 你们只是推测!
You got no eyes, you got no ears, you got nothing but assumptions!
是我下令进攻 我行使我的权力
I called for the breach. It Was conducted with my authority.
到此为止
Not anymore.
我们正式接管 联邦调查局不能不管了
We're taking over. FBI cannot stand by and let this situation continue.
- 别让我走 听我说  - 我们请你离开 中尉
- Don't take me off. Listen to me. - We're asking you to leave, lieutenant.
我刚才骗了他 可他知道我的目的
All right, I bluffed him' but he knows what I was doing.
请你的人撤出 由突击队顶替...
We need to rotate your men...
他认为刚才有人要杀他!
He thinks someone just tried to kill him!
我们进入 全面攻击
We're going in. Full breach.
别这样 听我说 全面攻击的话 所有人都会死
Don't do it. Listen. You breach, everyone's gonna die.
明白吗? 所有人都会死
Understand that? Everyone's gonna die.
也许你们有人希望这样 可我不希望!
Maybe that's what some of you wanna have happen, but I don't!
我被叫来救这个人 带他出来!
I was brought here to save this man's life and bring him out' all right?
没理由要伤害人质
There's no reason to jeopardize hostages.
你闭嘴!
Shut up!
特工 换掉我的人是错的 要换谈判专家 很好
Agent Moran, this is a mistake. You wanna change negotiators' fine.
给罗曼30秒机会...
But you give Roman a 30-second window of opportunity...
...他都会利用
...he'll exploit it.
必须继续包围 我的人已就位 他们能处理
We gotta keep him locked down. My men can handle it.
领教过他们的处理方法
We've seen what your men can handle.
让我留下
Please.
你的人留在原地 我们的人支援...
Your men stay in place. Our men will support yours...
- ...不过你要执行我们的命令  - 赛比安 你走吧
- ...but you'll execute orders that we give. - You're off' Sabian.
真不敢相信 满屋子人都想进去杀了他
I can't believe this. I'm just surrounded by people who wanna go in and kill him.
这人你们称他为朋友 这与我毫无关系!
This is the guy you called your friend. I got nothing invested in this!
我想知道为什么!
I wonder why that is!
也许有一天会知道
Maybe someday we'll find out.
谈判结束了
No more negotiating.
送塞比安先生上车
Would you please escort Mr. Sabian to his car?
中尉
Lieutenant.
这边请
This way' sir.
急不可待要冲上去 你们自称是他的朋友
Dying to go up. You call yourselves his friends.
丹尼・罗曼 我是联邦调查局特工格瑞
Danny Roman' this is Agent Grey of the FBI.
克瑞斯・塞比安已被解除指挥权 现在由我负责
Chris Sabian has been relieved of his command and I'm in charge.
从现在起停止谈判
As of this mornent, all negotiations are suspended.
给你5分钟投降...
You have five minutes to surrender...
...否则我们进去逮捕你
...or we're coming in after you.
天哪 塞比安进去了
Oh' Christ. Sabian's going in.
丹尼 是我 我就上来
Danny, it's me. I'm on my way up.
丹尼 这不是你的错 我们都听见他承认了 有罪的是他不是你
Danny, this wasn't your fault. We all heard him confess. He Was guilty.
我知道
Yeah.
无所谓了
Well' what's it matter, Maggie?
内森死了 尼鲍姆死了
Nate's dead. Niebaum's dead.
电脑也完了
Computer's dead.
塞比安上来了
And, look, Sabian is coming upstairs now.
必须把尼鲍姆的话告诉他
You have to tell him what Niebaum said.
你要放弃? 那才是犯罪
What, you gonna give up now? Come on, that'd be a crime, man.
你们都听着...
Listen' all of you...
...对不起 把你们牵扯进来
...l'm sorry I got you into this.
很快就要结束了
This'll all be over soon.
丹尼 接电话 否则我们马上强行进入
Danny, pick up the phone or we will be forced to come in.
麦琪 请你转告我妻子
Maggie, would you tell my Wife something for me?
告诉她 我想信守诺言 我努力了
Just tell her I was trying to keep my promise.
嘿 丹尼
Hey, Danny.
尼鲍姆经常在家里工作
You know, Niebaum Worked at home just about as much as he worked here.
内森的录音可能保存在家里
He could've kept Nathan's taps there.
就你自己?
You alone?
你必须投降 我无法阻止他们 他们就到了
You gotta surrender now. I can't hold them back. They're coming up.
我只差一步 我知道发生了什么
I'm getting too close' Chris. I know What went down now.
尼鲍姆说: 赫尔曼 埃伦和阿尔金托都参与了
Niebaum told me Hellman, Allen and Argento are involved.
- 你没有证据  - 他有 尼鲍姆的交待我们都听见了
- You got no proof. - He does. Niebaum confessed. We all heard.
他们想把我们全杀掉 可你一点没帮我们
They're shooting us one by one and you fuckers aren't helping us.
- 你到底想不想帮我们?  - 谁下令进攻 贝克?
- Are you gonna help us or what? - Who called for the breach? Beck?
他说你先开枪 他的人还击 尼鲍姆是个意外
Yeah, but he says you fired first and Niebaum was an accident.
尼鲍姆不是死于意外 是死于谋杀!
Niebaum Was no accident. He was assassinated.
子弹全打在他胸口
He's got three bullets, center mass. Look.
克瑞斯 你不能否认有阴谋
Come on, Chris. You gotta admit something's going on.
那不重要了 死了两名警官 你杀了其中一个
It doesn't matter. Two cops are dead and you killed one.
我要赶在他们之前送你和人质出去
I need to get you and these hostages out of here before they come in.
结束了 丹尼!
Let's end this, Danny!
他们必须相信我能做到
They had to believe I Was capable of that.
只死了一个警察 是被陷害我的人打死的
There's only one dead cop up here, killed by the men who tried to set me up.
内森录下赫尔曼等人的谈话
now, I know Nate tapped Hellman and the others.
录音带可能在尼鲍姆家里 我能到那里就能结束此事
I think those taps are at Niebaum's. If I get there' I can end this.
他们会杀了你 除了投降 你无法活着出去
They're gonna kill you. Understand? You got no way out unless you surrender.
你关掉暖气已给了我出路
You gave me a way out when you shut the heat off.
你知道你有其他办法能帮我
now, you know there's another way you can help me.
你看错我了
You were wrong about me.
我若没看错他们?
What if I'm right about them?
但你若看错我了?
But What if you're wrong about me?
麦琪 打开手铐 都去会议室
Maggie. Uncuff yourself. Get in the conference room.
妈的
Shit.
开始全面进攻 击毙目标
Initiate full breach. Shoot on sight.
鲁迪 快走!
Come on, Rudy. Move, move!
给 麦琪 用这个
Here, Maggie, use this.
马库斯和鲁迪合用 弄湿它
Markus, split this betWeen you and Rudy. Wet it.
你知道怎么做 一会将有浓烟和催泪弹
You know the drill. There's gonna be a lot of gas and smoke.
给我钥匙
Let me have those keys.
别害怕 马上会来人救你们
Don't be scared. They're coming to save you in a minute.
关上门
Close the door.
趴下 趴下 趴在地上
down, down, down. On the ground, now.
- 快走  - 快走
- Move. - Move now.
当心!
Look out!
两人一组
Double up' now! now' now, now!
找到人质 不见罗曼
Found the hostages. No sign of Roman.
检查电梯井 所有通风口 地下室
Check the elevator shaft, check every vent, check the basement.
起来 跟我走!
Come on, get up. Let's go. Let's go!
找到斯科特
We found Scott.
他没事
He's alive.
想证明自己清白 给你个机会
You wanna prove your innocence, here's your chance.
你若走错一步...
But you make one wrong move...
...我就亲手杀了你 明白?
...and I'm gonna take you down myself. Understand?
想离开这里? 跟我来
All right, you wanna get out of here? Follow me.
只要他在 我们就能找到他
If he's in here, We'll find him.
他不在
He's not.
他早走了
He's gone mobile.
我是指挥官贝克 这次行动再次由我负责
This is Commander Beck. I am now back in charge of this operation.
你这是干什么?
What are you doing?
他离开大楼 就出了你的管辖区
If he's out of the building, he's no longer in your jurisdiction.
指挥中心
Dispatch.
疑犯可能徒步离开现场 通知所有巡逻车
Suspect may have left the scene, possibly on foot. Alert all units.
明白 通知所有巡逻车
Alerting all units.
对不起 中尉 能打开行李厢吗?
Sorry' lieutenant. Can We check the trunk?
我什么也不知道 发生了太多事
I don't know what the fuck was going on. A lot of shit happened out there.
你一定知道点什么
You must have some idea.
我想帮你们 可我发过誓不能说
You know something? I would really like to help' but my lips are sealed.
说实话我不相信你们
Frankly, I don't trust any of you fucking guys.
- 我对你们很失望  - 麦琪
- I'm very disappointed in all of you. - Maggie.
你必须帮助我们 我知道你的心情
You gotta help us out here. I know What you're feeling.
知道你同情丹尼...
I know you sympathize with Danny...
...可我们必须找到他 制止他再做危险的事
...but we need to stop him before he does something dangerous.
你不想再有人受伤害吧?
You don't Want anyone else hurt, do you?
你知道他在哪里 若不说就是妨碍执法
You know something, you don't tell us' that's obstruction of justice.
你想坐牢吗?
Wanna go to jail?
他去了尼鲍姆家
He went to Niebaum's house.
他为什么去那里?
Why did he go there?
麦琪?
Maggie?
他为什么去那里?
Why did he go there?
(办公室档案: 调查中-监听)
什么也没有
There's nothing here.
内森遇害前去见谁? 琳达说了?
Chris. Who did Nate see the night before he Was killed? Did Linda tell you?
他去找你 可你不在警局
Yeah. He went to see you' but you weren't at the precinct.
你没时间了
You're running out of time, Danny.
- 指挥中心 我是指挥官贝克  - 继续
- Dispatch, this is Commander Beck. - Go ahead.
派空中分队到艾迪逊大街1300号
I need an air unit deployed to the 1300 block of Addison.
派特别行动队到艾迪逊街口与我汇合
Have available HBT units meet me at the corner of Addison and Iroquois.
需要一名队长继续清查市府大楼
I also need an HPT supervisor to clear the building.
收到 随后安排
Copy. Will relay.
丹尼 什么也没有 一切都结束了
Come on, Danny, there's nothing here. It's over.
我带你去自首 还有机会
That's it, I'm taking you in' man. You had your chance.
听着 现在不要背叛我 你说了给我时间
Look, look. Don't screw me now. You said you were gonna give me time.
我知道是他们杀了内森
now, look. I know these are the bastards that killed Nate.
我现在只需要...
now, all I need...
...2分钟和你的对讲机
...is two minutes. Just two minutes and your radio, all right?
我能成功 给我!
I can make this work. Come on!
站住别动 赫尔曼!
Hold it right there, Hellman.
走过来 我就杀了你们
You come down this hallway, I'll shoot you one by one.
丹尼 丹尼・罗曼
Hell, Danny. Danny Roman.
都结束了
Come on, it's all over, huh?
你只要坐几年牢
You'll do a little time.
凯伦会有人照顾
Karen will be taken care of, okay?
没人受伤害
Nobody gets hurt.
好吗? 投降吧!
All right? Come on. Surrender.
投降个屁
Surrender, my ass.
我有两张磁盘 上面有你的声音 是内森录下的
I've got two disks with your voices on them. Nate's taps.
来吧!
Come on down the hall!
我有15发子弹 每人5发
I got 15 shots here. That's five apiece.
罗曼 无论你耍什么花招都没有用了
Hell Whatever you're trying to pull, Roman, it's not gonna work.
趁还没死人 别再胡闹 出来吧
Stop this shit and come out before someone gets killed.
我知道有人主使 你们自己偷不了那么多钱
Look, I know somebody else was in charge. You couldn't have pulled this off yourself.
丹尼老兄 你全弄错了
Danny, man, you got this all wrong.
我没错 你很紧张 阿尔金托
No, I got it right. Is that why you sound so nervous, Argento?
- 是你杀了尼鲍姆和内森?  - 丹尼 这太可笑了!
- You killed Niebaum and Nate? - Danny, that's absurd!
他们会让你...
Come on. You know your guys out there...
...被处死以换取减刑
...gonna leave you hanging for murder one while they plea down.
为自己留条活路 趁现在还来得及
Make a deal for yourself while you still can, Argento.
我发誓我们不懂你在说什么
Danny, I swear to you we don't know what you're talking about.
继续装傻!
All right, play dumb.
你们怎么会傻到让人录了音?
how could you dumb fucks let somebody get you on tape?
你听听! 别胡说了 快出来!
Come on. Listen to you. Why don't you stop this shit and come out?
你们这群混蛋继续扯谈好了 你全做错了
All right, keep talking' asshole. You've already done everything wrong.
你让我活着 我跟你们斗 我赢了
You left me alive, me against you, and I Won.
你混蛋! 混蛋!
Hey, fuck you, huh? Fuck you!
我跟你说: 我不怕你有什么鬼证据
Let me tell you: I don't give a fuck what kind of evidence you got. Know Why?
因为我不会让你活着出去!
Because you're not gonna make it out of here alive, motherfucker!
退下
Stand down.
你们把枪放下 都出去
Put your weapons down and move your asses out of here now.
- 弗罗斯? - 丹尼 是我 弗罗斯
- Frost? - Yeah. Danny, it's me, Frost.
我命令他们出去 把他们锁在外面
Yeah, Danny, I'm ordering them off. I'm locking them out now.
只剩下你和我
It's just you and me' buddy.
听见了吗 丹尼?
You hear that, Danny?
他们走了
They're gone.
听着 丹尼...
Listen' Danny...
...我知道你很害怕
...I know you're scared.
知道你不相信任何人
I know you don't trust anyone.
发生了很多事
A lot of shit Went down.
有些事连我自己也不明白
I don't even understand some of it myself.
出来吧 丹尼 我支持你
Come on out, Danny. You have my support.
你有什么证据 拿出来吧
Any evidence you have, let's just bring it out there.
弗罗斯 出来
Hey, Frost. Come on.
你在这里干什么? 赛比安
What the hell are you doing here, Sabian?
- 干你要干的事  - 你在说什么?
- Finishing what you started. - What are you talking about?
我带罗曼出去投降
Roman is going out with me.
就我俩 我们不相信其他人
No one else. Alone. We can't trust anyone else.
说的对
Yeah, that's right.
我们不知道该相信谁
We don't know who to trust, do we?
爱看西部片吗 弗罗斯?
Do you like Westerns, Frost?
问这是什么意思?
What's the fuck is that supposed to mean?
我爱看西部片 百看不厌
I like Westerns. I can't get enough of them.
一直都在看
Watch them all the time.
我最爱看最后英雄壮烈牺牲
My favorites have always been where the hero dies at the end.
- 记得《原野奇侠》吗 丹尼?  - 什么?
- You remember Shane, Danny? - What?
你说的对 最后西恩死了
I think you're right. Shane died at the end.
你杀了内森 我杀了丹尼...
So you killed Nathan, I killed Danny...
...现在我的手和你的一样脏...
...and now my hands are just as dirty as yours...
...只是我手里有证据...
...only I still have the evidence...
...所以我是谈判占上风的一方
...so I'd say I'm in a very good position to negotiate.
想做交易?
So you wanna deal?
跟我谈吧
You deal With me.
谈判时间有限 马上会有干扰...
There's a time limit on these negotiations because we're about to be interrupted...
...咱们开门见山 分我一份
...so let's do this quickly. I want in.
你们所有非法所得的60%
Sixty percent of everything you've taken.
我不能给你 我没有的
I can't give you what I don't have.
我那份已花掉很多
You see, I spent a lot of my take.
不知道埃伦和阿尔金托还剩多少
I don't know how much Allen' Hellman and Argento have.
陷害罗曼用了不少
We used a lot of it to set Roman up.
要你没有的50%
All right. Fifty percent of what you don't have.
- 30%  - 45%
- Thirty percent. - Forty-five.
35%
Thirty-five.
你应该当谈判专家
You should've been a negotiator.
对
Right.
我要消毁所有证据
I want all the evidence destroyed.
成交
Deal.
全都在这里?
This is everything, huh?
嗯
Hmm.
你说呢?
What do you think?
丹尼・罗曼中弹
Danny Roman's been shot.
他死了
He's dead.
我叫人来帮你
Let's get you some help.
起来 扶着我
Come on. Here we go.
我们走
That's it. Come on.
爬起来
There you go.
有警员受伤!
We got an officer down in here!
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
如果你打破沉默...
If you give up the right to remain silent...
...你所说的一切将被用于指控你...
...anything you say can be used against you...
不 不 不...
No, no, no...
不能这么便宜了你
You're not gonna get off that easy.
凯伦 等等
Karen, wait.
- 来人帮忙!  - 有警员受伤!
- Get some help here. - We got an injured cop here.
握住我的手
Give me your hand.
丹尼 知道我怎么想的?
Danny, you know what I thought.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起了
Sorry about that.
好计谋 克瑞斯
Nice bluff, Chris.
起作用了
Well' it Worked.
我想与他相比 你宁可挨我一枪
Anyway, I figured you'd rather be shot by me than by him.
是啊
Yeah.
你有个要求我刚办到
Here's the one demand I didn't meet yet.
很高兴能与你交谈 中尉
Nice talking to you, lieutenant.
谢谢
Thanks.
送他去医院
Let's get him out of here.
伊戈尔 封锁这个地区
Eagle' make sure this location is secured.
确保整条街道路通畅 有救护车要通过
I want this street cleared, right now! Got an ambulance coming through here.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer1733
快去!
Move it!
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer